<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
<channel>
	<title>Soybean and Corn Advisor</title>
	<description>Your Source for Global Soybean and Corn News</description>
<link>http://soybeansandcorn.com/</link>
<atom:link href="http://soybeansandcorn.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
`
	<item>
		<title>
		 	November 12, 2010: Soybeans in Southern Brazil Could Feel Affects of La Nina
        </title>
		<description>
			Planting conditions in central Brazil have improved with recent rainfall and now that approximately half of the Brazilian 2010/11 soybean crop has been planted, the second half of the planting is expected to proceed normally.  The biggest concern for Brazilian farmers continues to be the potential for dryer than normal weather during November and December resulting from La Nina.  
		</description>
		<link>
			http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Nov12_10-Soybeams-in-Southern-Brazil-Could-Feel-Affect-of-La-Nina
		</link>
		<guid>
			http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Nov12_10-Soybeams-in-Southern-Brazil-Could-Feel-Affect-of-La-Nina
		</guid>
	</item>

	<item>
		<title>
			November 12, 2010: GMO Crops Continue to Gain Acreage in Brazil
        </title>
		<description>
			While some farmers in Brazil feel there will be a niche market for conventional grains, the bigger trend in Brazil is for more genetically modified crop production.  In the state of Parana for example, three out of every four sacks of grain produced in 2010/11 will be GMO varieties.  In 2009/10, GMO crops accounted for a little more than 50% of the state's total production.  During the 2010/11 growing season GMO crops are expected to account for approximately 76% of the total grain production in the state.
		</description>
		<link>
			http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Nov12_10-GMO-Crops-Continues-to-Gain-Acreage-in-Brazil
		</link>
		<guid>
			http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Nov12_10-GMO-Crops-Continues-to-Gain-Acreage-in-Brazil
		</guid>
	</item>

	<item>
		<title>
		 	November 11, 2010: Mato Grosso Soybean Acreage Down, Cotton Acreage Up
        </title>
		<description>
			The high price of cotton and the delayed onset of the rains have farmers in Mato Grosso reassessing their soybean and cotton planting intensions.  Instead of planting a late crop of soybeans and then not having enough time to plant a second crop of cotton, a number of farmers in the state have decided not to plant soybeans at all and are opting to plant more full season cotton instead.
		</description>
		<link>
			http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Nov11_10-Mato-Grosso-Soybean-Acreage-Down-Cotton-Acreage-Up
		</link>
		<guid>
			http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Nov11_10-Mato-Grosso-Soybean-Acreage-Down-Cotton-Acreage-Up
		</guid>
	</item>

	<item>
		<title>
			November 11, 2010: Corn Acreage in Sao Paulo Pressured by Sugarcane Expansion 
        </title>
		<description>
			The 2010/11 full season corn acreage in the state of Sao Paulo fell for the second year in a row.  In 2009/10, farmers in the state planted 597,000 hectares of corn, which was 70,000 less than in 2008/09.  Estimates are that during the current growing season corn acreage in the state could fall again by as much as 15-20%.    
		</description>
		<link>
			http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Nov11_10-Corn-Acreage-in-Sao-Paulo-Pressured-by-Sugarcane-Expansion
		</link>
		<guid>
			http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Nov11_10-Corn-Acreage-in-Sao-Paulo-Pressured-by-Sugarcane-Expansion
		</guid>
	</item>

	<item>
		<title>
		 	November 10, 2010: Foreigners Face New Restrictions on Land Purchases in Brazil
        </title>
		<description>
			During the last two and a half years, foreign investors have purchased 1,152 properties in Brazil totaling 515,000 hectares.  This is the equivalent to the area of 22 soccer fields being purchased per hour by non-Brazilians.  This information was gathered by The Folha de Sao Paulo, a newspaper in Sao Paulo, who analyzed records from Incra (The National Colonization and Agrarian Reform Institute) from November of 2007 to May of 2010.  They looked at purchases made by individuals, companies, as well as purchases made by Brazilian companies that are controlled by non-Brazilians.
		</description>
		<link>
			http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Nov10_Foreigners-Face-New-Restrictions-on-Land-Purchaes-in-Brazil
		</link>
		<guid>
			http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Nov10_Foreigners-Face-New-Restrictions-on-Land-Purchaes-in-Brazil
		</guid>
	</item>

	<item>
		<title>
			November 10, 2010: Mato Grosso Farmers Will Have 75% Less Soy to Sell In January
        </title>
		<description>
			The extended dry season on Mato Grosso delayed the start of the soybean planting and it will also delay the beginning of the soybean harvest as well.  The Mato Grosso Institute of Agricultural Economics (Imea) estimates that the farmers in Mato Grosso will have 75% less soybeans to sell in January 2011 compared to January 2010.  Imea estimates that the farmers in Mato Grosso will harvest only 1.0 million tons of soybeans in January 2011 compared to 4 million tons harvested last January.  
		</description>
		<link>
			http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Nov10_10-Mato-Grosso-Farmers-Will-Have-75-Less-Soy-to-Sell-in-January
		</link>
		<guid>
			http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Nov10_10-Mato-Grosso-Farmers-Will-Have-75-Less-Soy-to-Sell-in-January
		</guid>
	</item>

	<item>
		<title>
		 November 9, 2010: Guidelines for non-GMO Grain Being Developed in Brazil
        </title>
		<description>
			The Brazilian Association of Non-GMO Grain Producers (Abrange) is in the process of developing guidelines for farmers so they can certify that their grain is non-GMO.  Some producers in Brazil feel there is a niche market for conventional grain production and they are in the process of developing a certification program that would help farmers capture that market.  The guidelines are expected to be complete and published by the end of the year.  
		</description>
		<link>
			http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Nov9_10-Guidelines-for-non-GMO-Grain-Being-Developed-in-Brazil
		</link>
		<guid>
			http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Nov9_10-Guidelines-for-non-GMO-Grain-Being-Developed-in-Brazil
		</guid>
	</item>

	<item>
		<title>
		November 9, 2010: Since 2006, 800 Repossessions Have Occurred in Mato Grosso
        </title>
		<description>
			Over the last 20 days, farmers in at least five municipalities of Mato Grosso have seen some of their equipment repossessed by banks and equipment manufactures due to defaults on their equipment loans.  The amount of repossessions in the state started to intensify in August and most of the equipment that is being repossessed are planters, which is ironic sine this the planting season in Mato Grosso.  
		</description>
		<link>
			http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Nov9_10-Since-2006-800-Repossessions-Have-Occurred-in-Mato-Grosso
		</link>
		<guid>
			http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Nov9_10-Since-2006-800-Repossessions-Have-Occurred-in-Mato-Grosso
		</guid>
	</item>

	<item>
		<title>
		 November 8, 2010: Farmers in Mato Grosso Planting Around the Clock to Catch Up
        </title>
		<description>
			Frustrations mounted daily as farmers in Mato Grosso were forced to wait for a rain before they could start planting their 2010/11 soybean crop.  In Campo Verde for example, located in southeastern Mato Grosso, the first significant rainfall of the season fell only last Sunday when more than three inches of rain were recorded.  For the farmers in the region, this was the first rain after six months of dry weather. 
		</description>
		<link>
			http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Nov8_10-Farmers-in-Mato-Grosso-Planting-Around-the-Clock-to-Catch-Up
		</link>
		<guid>
			http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Nov8_10-Farmers-in-Mato-Grosso-Planting-Around-the-Clock-to-Catch-Up
		</guid>
	</item>

	<item>
		<title>
		November 8, 2010: India Imported 19% of Brazil's 2009 Sugar Exports
        </title>
		<description>
			After a series of poor sugarcane harvests in India, the country became the largest importer of Brazilian sugar in 2009.  During 2009, Brazil produced 33 million tons of sugar and exported 24 million tons.  Of the total Brazilian exports in 2009, India imported 4.6 million tons or 19% of the total.  The second largest importer of Brazilian sugar in 2009 was Russia at 2.7 million tons.
		</description>
		<link>
			http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Nov8_10-India-Importing-19-of-Brazils-2009-Sugar-Exports
		</link>
		<guid>
			http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Nov8_10-India-Importing-19-of-Brazils-2009-Sugar-Exports
		</guid>
	</item>

	<item>
		<title>
		  November 5, 2010: Argentina Planting Progressing Ahead of Schedule
        </title>
		<description>
			Prior to the start of the planting season in Argentina, there was widespread concern that La Nina would result in dry weather in Argentina that could disrupt the planting of 2010/11 corn and soybean crops.  Up until now, La Nina has not affected spring planting which has progressed ahead of the normal planting pace.  Farmers are taking advantage of the good conditions to plant their crops as quickly as possible.
		</description>
		<link>
			http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Nov5_10-Argentina-Planting-Progressing-Ahead-of-Schedule
		</link>
		<guid>
		http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Nov5_10-Argentina-Planting-Progressing-Ahead-of-Schedule
		</guid>
	</item>

	<item>
		<title>
		November 5, 2010: Biodiesel Capacity Continues to Expand in Brazil
        </title>
		<description>
			In the last several weeks, three large multinational agricultural companies have announced plans to build biodiesel plants in Brazil.  Cargill, ADM, and Noble all plan to greatly expand their biodiesel production in the country.  
		</description>
		<link>
			http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Nov5_10-Biodisel-Capacity-Continues-to-Expand-in-Brazil
		</link>
		<guid>
			http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Nov5_10-Biodisel-Capacity-Continues-to-Expand-in-Brazil
		</guid>
	</item>

	<item>
		<title>
		   November 4, 2010: High Prices Could Spur Increased Safrinha Corn Acres in Parana
        </title>
		<description>
			While soybean planting has been slower than normal in Mato Grosso, it has been faster than normal in the state of Parana.  Over the last four years, farmers in Parana have planted on average 25% of their intended soybean acres before the end of October.  This year, farmers in the state had managed to plant more than 50% of their soybeans before the end of October.  
		</description>
		<link>
			http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Nov4_10-High-Prices-Could-Spur-Increased-Safrinha-Corn-Acres-in-Parana
		</link>
		<guid>
		http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Nov4_10-High-Prices-Could-Spur-Increased-Safrinha-Corn-Acres-in-Parana
		</guid>
	</item>

	<item>
		<title>
		November 4, 2010: United States Surpasses Brazil in Ethanol Exports
        </title>
		<description>
			By the end of the first semester of 2010, the United States had taken over the role from Brazil as the world's leading exporter of ethanol.  A weak dollar as well as heavy investments in the ethanol industry and import tariffs helped propel the United States into the lead.  
		</description>
		<link>
			http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Nov4_10-United-States-Surpasses-Brazil-in-Ethanol-Exports
		</link>
		<guid>
			http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Nov4_10-United-States-Surpasses-Brazil-in-Ethanol-Exports
		</guid>
	</item>

	<item>
		<title>
		   November 3, 2010: Brazilian Cotton Acreage Certain to Increase in 2010/11
        </title>
		<description>
			Record high international cotton prices are encouraging Brazilian farmers to increase their 2010/11 cotton acreage.  The Brazilian 2010/11 cotton acreage in Brazil is expected to increase 26% from 835,000 hectares grown last year to 1.05 million hectares this year.  With all the current excitement surrounding cotton, those estimates may actually end up being low.
		</description>
		<link>
			http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Nov3_10-Brazilian-Cotton-Acreage-Certain-to-Increase-in-201011
		</link>
		<guid>
		http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Nov3_10-Brazilian-Cotton-Acreage-Certain-to-Increase-in-201011
		</guid>
	</item>

	<item>
		<title>
		November 3, 2010: Farmers Want Brazil's New President to Focus on Infrastructure
        </title>
		<description>
			When Ms. Dilma Rousseff assumes office as Brazil's first female president on January 1st, the number one issue the agricultural community wants her to address is the improvement of the country's infrastructure.  According to Joel Naegele, vice president of the National Agricultural Society, their most urgent need is to reduce the cost of transportation by improving the infrastructure.
		</description>
		<link>
			http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Nov3_10-Farmers-Want-Brazils-New-President-to-Focus-on-Infrastructure
		</link>
		<guid>
			http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Nov3_10-Farmers-Want-Brazils-New-President-to-Focus-on-Infrastructure
		</guid>
	</item>

	<item>
		<title>
		   November 2, 2010: Strong Soybean Prices Accelerate Forward Selling in Brazil
        </title>
		<description>
			While many farmers in central Brazil spent the month of October waiting for enough rain to start planting their soybean crop, they continued to be aggressive sellers of the 2010/11 soybean crop which they had not yet planted.  Estimates are that approximately 45% of the 2010/11 soybean crop in Mato Grosso has already been sold compared to just 27% last year at this time.  
		</description>
		<link>
			http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Nov2_10-Strong-Soybean-Prices-Accelerate-Forward-Selling-in-Brazil
		</link>
		<guid>
		http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Nov2_10-Strong-Soybean-Prices-Accelerate-Forward-Selling-in-Brazil
		</guid>
	</item>

	<item>
		<title>
		November 2, 2010: Safrinha Corn Acreage in Mato Grosso Could Decline 
        </title>
		<description>
			The delayed soybean planting in Mato Grosso could result in lower <i>safrinha</i> corn acreage in the state.  Generally speaking, if soybeans are planted during the month of November, there is not enough time to plant a second crop of corn after the soybean harvest without risking significant yield losses in the corn.  The state of Mato Grosso planted 1.94 million hectares of <i>safrinha</i> corn last year which was the largest <i>safrinha</i> corn acreage in Brazil.
		</description>
		<link>
			http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Nov2_10-Safrinha-Corn-Acreage-in-Mato-Grosso-Could-Decline
		</link>
		<guid>
			http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Nov2_10-Safrinha-Corn-Acreage-in-Mato-Grosso-Could-Decline
		</guid>
	</item>

	<item>
		<title>
		   November 1, 2010: Brazil-China Trade Commission to Discuss Trade/Currency Policy
        </title>
		<description>
			Brazilian officials have finally managed to schedule a meeting in Beijing to discuss trade relations between Brazil and China as well as China's currency policy.  A trade commission between the two countries was set up in 2004 for the purpose of discussing trade issues, but the commission has only managed to meet one time in six years.  Brazil has been trying to schedule a meeting of the commission for two years, but Chinese officials continued to disagree on agenda items.  The two sides have finally agreed on an agenda and the second meeting of the commission is scheduled for November 15 and 16 in Beijing.
		</description>
		<link>
			http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Nov1_10-Brazil-China-Trade-Commission-to-Discuss-Trade-Currency-Policy
		</link>
		<guid>
			http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Nov1_10-Brazil-China-Trade-Commission-to-Discuss-Trade-Currency-Policy
		</guid>
	</item>

	<item>
		<title>
		 November 1, 2010: Banks in Mato Grosso Resume Repossessing Ag Equipment
        </title>
		<description>
			After a brief two week extension of the grace period during which farmers could renegotiate their delinquent equipment loans, banks in Mato Grosso have once again started to repossess equipment from farmers for lack of payment.  The majority of equipment being repossessed is planters, which is ironic because this is the peak of the planting period in the state.
		</description>
		<link>
			http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Nov1_10-Banks-in-Mato-Grosso-Resume-Repossesing-Ag-Equipment
		</link>
		<guid>
			http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Nov1_10-Banks-in-Mato-Grosso-Resume-Repossesing-Ag-Equipment
		</guid>
	</item>

	<item>
		<title>
		   October 29, 2010: Barges Moving Again on the Madeira River in Northwestern Brazil 
        </title>
		<description>
			After an extended dry season and several months of low water levels, barges are once again carrying soybeans down the Madeira River in northwest Brazil on their way to ports on the Amazon River.  The two grain companies that use the river to barge soybeans, Amaggi and Cargill, both reported that their barging operations have resumed operations after being suspended in August.  In August, the water level on the Madeira River was the second lowest in forty years.  The only time the water level was lower was in 2005. 
		</description>
		<link>
			http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Oct29_10-Barges-Moving-Again-on-the-Madeira-River-in-Northwest-Brazil
		</link>
		<guid>
			http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Oct29_10-Barges-Moving-Again-on-the-Madeira-River-in-Northwest-Brazil
		</guid>
	</item>

	<item>
		<title>
		 October 29, 2010: 23 Sugar/ethanol Mills in Brazil are Already Closed for the Season
        </title>
		<description>
			The amount of sugarcane processed in southern Brazil continued its decline during the first half of October.  This is a continuation of a decline that stated several months ago when the extended dry season resulted in reduced sugarcane tonnage.  The amount of sugarcane processed during the first half of October was 4% less than the last fifteen days of September and 30% less than the first fifteen days of September.
		</description>
		<link>
			http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Oct29_10-22-Sugar-Ethanol-Mills-in-Brazil-are-Already-Closed-for-the-Season
		</link>
		<guid>
			http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Oct29_10-22-Sugar-Ethanol-Mills-in-Brazil-are-Already-Closed-for-the-Season
		</guid>
	</item>

	<item>
		<title>
		   October 28, 2010: Brazilian Farmers Aggressively Forward Selling Cotton 
        </title>
		<description>
			Cotton farmers in Brazil are taking advantage of record cotton prices to forward sell their anticipated 2010/11 cotton crop.  Nationwide, 45% of the 2010/11 crop has been sold and in western Bahia the percentage is even higher at 60% and it could hit 80% in the next few months. 
		</description>
		<link>
			http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Oct28_10-Brazilian-Farmers-Aggresively-Forward-Selling-Cotton
		</link>
		<guid>
		http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Oct28_10-Brazilian-Farmers-Aggresively-Forward-Selling-Cotton
		</guid>
	</item>

	<item>
		<title>
		 October 28, 2010: Mato Grosso Farmers Have Already Sold 45% of Soy Production
        </title>
		<description>
			According to the Mato Grosso Institute of Agricultural Economics (Imea), farmers in Mato Grosso have already sold 45% of their anticipated 2010/11 soybean production.  This is significantly more than the 29% that was sold last year at this time.  A sack of soybeans in Mato Grosso (60 kilograms or 2.2 bushels) is currently selling at US$ 20 compared to the US$ 14 it was selling for last year at this time.  If there had not been a delayed start to soybean planting in the state, the forward selling percentage would be even higher.
		</description>
		<link>
			http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Oct28_10-Mato-Grosso-Farmers-Have-Already-Sold-45-Soy-Production
		</link>
		<guid>
			http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Oct28_10-Mato-Grosso-Farmers-Have-Already-Sold-45-Soy-Production
		</guid>
	</item>

	<item>
		<title>
		  October 28, 2010: Brazilian Producers Want a B20 Biodiesel Blend by 2020
        </title>
		<description>
			The Brazilian Biodiesel Union (Ubrabio) will petition the Brazilian government to raise the percentage of vegetable oil in diesel fuel from its current B5 blend to a B20 blend by the year 2020.  The group has indicated for several years that the industry has the capacity to increase the blend immediately and to keep increasing it in the future. 
		</description>
		<link>
			http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Oct28_10-Brazilian-Producers-Want-a-B20-Biodiesel-Blend-by-2020	
		</link>
		<guid>
			http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Oct28_10-Brazilian-Producers-Want-a-B20-Biodiesel-Blend-by-2020
		</guid>
	</item>


	<item>
		<title>
		   October 27, 2010: Brazilian Farmers Seek Niche for Conventional Grain Production
        </title>
		<description>
			While the use of GMO soybean and corn varieties in Brazil continues to increase, some farmers in Brazil feel there will continue to be a market for conventional crops (non-GMO) especially in the European Union.  Brazil's main competitors for international markets are the United States and Argentina and both of those countries have gone almost completely to GMO crop production, which opens an opportunity for Brazilian producers who still grow conventional corn and soybeans.
		</description>
		<link>
			http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Oct27_10-Brazilian-Farmers-Seek-Niche-for-Conventional-Grain-Production		
		</link>
		<guid>
			http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Oct27_10-Brazilian-Farmers-Seek-Niche-for-Conventional-Grain-Production
		</guid>
	</item>

	<item>
		<title>
		  October 27, 2010: Safrinha Corn Accounts for 38-40% of Brazil's Total Corn Prod.
        </title>
		<description>
			Brazilian farmers continue to turn more and more to <i>safrinha</i> corn production to replace the traditional full season corn production.  Over the last ten years, the percentage of the Brazilian corn crop produced as the <i>safrinha</i> has increased from 15% of the total Brazilian corn crop in 1999 to 38% of the total in 2009.  In central Brazil (Mato Grosso and Goias), nearly all the corn today is grown as a second crop following soybeans.  In Mato Grosso for example, the 2010/11 <i>safrinha</i> corn crop is expected to produce 8.7 million tons compared to only 300,000 tons for the full season corn crop.
		</description>
		<link>
			http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Oct27_10-Safrinha-Corn-Accounts-for-38-40-of-Brazils-Total-Corn-Prod
		</link>
		<guid>
			http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Oct27_10-Safrinha-Corn-Accounts-for-38-40-of-Brazils-Total-Corn-Prod
		</guid>
	</item>


	<item>
		<title>
		    October 26, 2010: John Deer Expanding Sugarcane Harvester Manufacturing in Brazil
        </title>
		<description>
			John Deere has announced plans to expand its sugarcane harvester manufacturing facility in Catalao, Goias.  The factory was inaugurated in 1999 and it remains John Deere's only factory outside the United States dedicated to the manufacture of sugarcane harvesters.  There are only two manufactures of sugarcane harvesters in Brazil and the demand is so great that customers must wait months to take delivery of a new harvester.  John Deere is investing R$ 60 million over four years to expand the facility.  The principal markets for these harvesters are Sao Paulo, Goias, Minas Gerais, Mato Grosso, Mato Grosso do Sul, and Parana.  
		</description>
		<link>
			http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Oct26_10-John-Deer-Expanding-Sugarcane-Harvester-Manufactering-in-Brazil		
		</link>
		<guid>
			http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Oct26_10-John-Deer-Expanding-Sugarcane-Harvester-Manufactering-in-Brazil
		</guid>
	</item>

	<item>
		<title>
		  October 26, 2010: Cargill Announces Its First Biodiesel Plant in Brazil
        </title>
		<description>
			Cargill announced this week that they will build their first biodiesel plant in Brazil.  It will be located adjacent to one of their existing soybean crushing plants in Tres Lagoas, Mato Grosso do Sul.  The facility will be operational in 2012 and it will produce 200,000 tons of biodiesel per year.  The total investment in the project is R$ 130 million.
		</description>
		<link>
			http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Oct26_10-Cargill-Announces-Its-First-Biodiesel-Plant-in-Brazil
		</link>
		<guid>
			http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Oct26_10-Cargill-Announces-Its-First-Biodiesel-Plant-in-Brazil
		</guid>
	</item>

	<item>
		<title>
		    October 25, 2010: Corn and Soy Planting Window in Brazil Narrower than Normal
        </title>
		<description>
			Farmers in southern Brazil continue to be concerned about the possibility that La Nina could result in periods of dry weather during November and December.  If these dryer than normal conditions do develop, meteorologists feel they will most likely develop in southern Brazil in Parana and Rio Grande do Sul.  As a result, agronomists have been advising farmers that they need to spread out their risks if at all possible.
		</description>
		<link>
			http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Oct25_10-Corn-and-Soy-Planting-Window-in-Brazil-Narrower-than-Normal		
		</link>
		<guid>
			http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Oct25_10-Corn-and-Soy-Planting-Window-in-Brazil-Narrower-than-Normal
		</guid>
	</item>

	<item>
		<title>
		  October 25, 2010: Brazil Sets New Record for Sugar Exports in September
        </title>
		<description>
			During the last twelve months ending in September, Brazil exported 72 billion dollars worth of agricultural products, setting a new record for the period.  The soybean complex was the most valuable export, but sugar and the meat complex recorded very strong sales as well.
		</description>
		<link>
			http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Oct25_10-Brazil-Sets-New-Record-for-Sugar-Exports-in-September
		</link>
		<guid>
			http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Oct25_10-Brazil-Sets-New-Record-for-Sugar-Exports-in-September
		</guid>
	</item>

	<item>
		<title>
		    October 22, 2010: More than Half of Soy Oil in Mato Grosso Used for Biodiesel
        </title>
		<description>
			Biodiesel production in Mato Grosso, which is already the largest producer in Brazil, is expected to increase six fold over the next five years from 285,000 cubic meters produced in 2010 to 1.8 million cubic meters expected to be produced in 2015.  As a result, more than half of the soybean oil produced in the state is currently being used to produce biodiesel and that percentage is expected to continue increasing.  Currently, 80% of the feedstock used for biodiesel production in Brazil is soybean oil. 
		</description>
		<link>
			http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Oct22_10-More-Than-Half-of-Soy-Oil-in-Mato-Grosso-Used-for-Biodiesell		
		</link>
		<guid>
			http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Oct22_10-More-Than-Half-of-Soy-Oil-in-Mato-Grosso-Used-for-Biodiesell
		</guid>
	</item>

	<item>
		<title>
		  October 22, 2010: Embrapa and Basf to Release GMO Soybeans in Brazil in 2012 
        </title>
		<description>
			Brazilian soybean farmers will soon have a choice concerning what type of GMO soybeans they wish to plant on their property.  Embrapa (the national agricultural research service) is set to release its first GMO soybean varieties to the Brazilian market in 2012.
		</description>
		<link>
			http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Oct22_10-Embrapa-and-Basf-to-Release-GMO-Soybeans-in-Brazil-in-2012
		</link>
		<guid>
			http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Oct22_10-Embrapa-and-Basf-to-Release-GMO-Soybeans-in-Brazil-in-2012
		</guid>
	</item>
	
	<item>
		<title>
		    October 21, 2010: 100 k ha of Soy in Mato Grosso May be Switched to Cotton Instead
        </title>
		<description>
			The delays in soybean planting in Mato Grosso has farmers in the state wondering if there will be enough time after the soybeans are harvested to still plant a second crop of corn or cotton.  In some parts of Mato Grosso the soybean planting has been delayed 30 days or more and planting will not commence until the rainfall frequency increases. 
		</description>
		<link>
			http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Oct21_10-100-k-ha-of-Soy-in-Mato-Grosso-May-be-Switched-to-Cotton-Instead		
		</link>
		<guid>
			http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Oct21_10-100-k-ha-of-Soy-in-Mato-Grosso-May-be-Switched-to-Cotton-Instead
		</guid>
	</item>

	<item>
		<title>
		  October 21, 2010: Brazil Continues to Lead the World in Orange Juice Exports
        </title>
		<description>
			Brazil is the largest exporter of orange in the world and the Brazilian juice exporters have largely avoided the logistical bottlenecks that plague exporters of other commodities from Brazil.  According to Christian Lohbauer, president of the National Citrus Juice Exporters Association (Citrus-BR), the reason why the orange juice exporters have avoided the problems so common at other Brazilian ports is because they use exclusively private facilities and not facilities operated by local or state governments.
		</description>
		<link>
			http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Oct21_10-Brazil-Contiunes-to-Lead-the-World-in-Orange-Juice-Eports
		</link>
		<guid>
			http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Oct21_10-Brazil-Contiunes-to-Lead-the-World-in-Orange-Juice-Eports
		</guid>
	</item>

	<item>
		<title>
		    October 20, 2010: Soybean Planting Pace in Brazil Slower Than Last Year and Uneven
        </title>
		<description>
			Nationwide the Brazilian soybean crop is approximately 8% planted compared to 13% last year and 8% average.  Even though planting pace is about average, it's slower than average in central Brazil and faster than average in southern Brazil.  Below is a look at the three main 
		</description>
		<link>
			http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Oct20_10-Soybean-Planting-Pace-in-Brazil-Slower-Than-Last-Year-and-Uneven		
		</link>
		<guid>
			http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Oct20_10-Soybean-Planting-Pace-in-Brazil-Slower-Than-Last-Year-and-Uneven
		</guid>
	</item>

	<item>
		<title>
		  October 20, 2010: Mato Grosso Has Largest Cattle Herd in Brazil 
        </title>
		<description>
			Mato Grosso is famous for its soybean production, but the state also has the largest cattle herd in Brazil as well.  According to the Mato Grosso Institute of Agricultural Economics (Imea), in 2009 there were 110,000 property owners in Mato Grosso involved in cattle ranching and 40 thousand jobs in the state are directly related to cattle ranching.  In 2009, there were 27 million head of cattle in Mato Grosso, which is 75% more than the 15 million head recorded in 1996.  In 2009, 4.2 million head of cattle were processed in the various meat packing facilities in the state generating R$ 4.2 billion in income for the state's cattle ranchers.  Brazil is also the second largest beef exported in the world.
		</description>
		<link>
			http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Oct20_10-Mato-Grosso-Has-Largest-Cattle-Herd-in-Brazil
		</link>
		<guid>
			http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Oct20_10-Mato-Grosso-Has-Largest-Cattle-Herd-in-Brazil
		</guid>
	</item>


	<item>
		<title>
		    October 19, 2010: Mato Grosso Farmers Have Already Sold 40% of Their Soy Crop
        </title>
		<description>
			In contrast to the slow start in planting their 2010/11 soybean crop, the farmers in Mato Grosso have been aggressively forward selling their anticipated soybean production.  According to the Mato Grosso Institute of Agricultural Economics (Imea), approximately 40% of the 2010/11 soybean crop in the state has already been sold.  The fastest forward selling is occurring in the western part of the state where the rainfall has been more widespread.  The slowest selling is occurring in the north-central part of the state where many farmers are still waiting for enough rain to start planting.
		</description>
		<link>
			http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Oct19_10-Mato-Grosso-Farmers-Have-Already-Sold-40-of-Their-Soy-Crop
		</link>
		<guid>
			http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Oct19_10-Mato-Grosso-Farmers-Have-Already-Sold-40-of-Their-Soy-Crop
		</guid>
	</item>

	<item>
		<title>
		  October 19, 2010: Sugar More Profitable than Ethanol for Brazilian Sugar Mills 
        </title>
		<description>
			At the start of the season, sugarcane producers in Brazil had been expecting an increase in sugarcane production for the 2010/11 season, but an extended dry season has reduced tonnage and expectations now are that the crop will be 3.5% less than last year.  After nearly five months of dry weather, rains returned to southeastern Brazil during the month of September, but the damage had already been done.
		</description>
		<link>
			http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Oct19_10-Sugar-More-Profitable-Than-Ethanol-For-Brazilian-Sugar-Mills
		</link>
		<guid>
			http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Oct19_10-Sugar-More-Profitable-Than-Ethanol-For-Brazilian-Sugar-Mills
		</guid>
	</item>

	<item>
		<title>
		    October 18, 2010: Mechanical Sugarcane Harvesting Increases Rural Unemployment
        </title>
		<description>
			The Brazilian government is forcing sugarcane producers to gradually eliminate the practice of manually cutting sugarcane and replacing it with mechanical harvesting.  The primary reason for the change is to eliminate the practice of burning off the dry leaves before the sugarcane is cut by hand.  The burning produces a large amount of air pollution that causes respiratory distress for people living nearby.  Much of the burning is done during the dry season, which makes the pollution even worse.  Without cleansing rains, the smoke and pollutants can remain in the lower atmosphere for weeks or months at a time.  The burning also releases significant amounts of greenhouse gasses which Brazil is trying to reduce.
		</description>
		<link>
			http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Oct18_10-Mechanical-Sugarcane-Harvesting-Increases-Rural-Unemployment
		</link>
		<guid>
			http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Oct18_10-Mechanical-Sugarcane-Harvesting-Increases-Rural-Unemployment
		</guid>
	</item>

	<item>
		<title>
		  October 18, 2010: Heavy Rains in September Delays Sugarcane Harvesting in Brazil 
        </title>
		<description>
			Virtually no rain fell in southeastern Brazil between early April and early September, but heavy rains during the second half of September have kept tractors out of the fields and reduced the amount of sugarcane harvested in the region.  Rainfall during the month of September in the state of Sao Paulo, which is the major sugarcane producing state in Brazil, was 60% greater than the average precipitation during the month.  On average, the sugarcane harvesters were out of the fields in southeastern Brazil for seven days during September compared to an average of three days.  According the Union of Sugarcane Industries (Unica), 27.16 million tons of sugarcane was processed during the second half of September, which is a decline of 27% compared to the previous year.  This is also a 35% reduction compared to the 42 million tons processed during the second half of August.
		</description>
		<link>
			http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Oct18_10-Heavy-Rains-in-September-Delays-Sugarcane-Harvesting-in-Brazil
		</link>
		<guid>
			http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Oct18_10-Heavy-Rains-in-September-Delays-Sugarcane-Harvesting-in-Brazil
		</guid>
	</item>

	<item>
		<title>
		    October 15, 2010: Currency Exchange Rate Aids Brazilian Millers Import Wheat 
        </title>
		<description>
			Farmers in southern Brazil are in the midst of harvesting their 2010 wheat crop and they are expecting the yields and the quality of the grain to be much better than in 2009.  Parana is the largest wheat producing state in Brazil and three quarters of the 2010 wheat crop has already been harvested.  The state of Parana is expected to produce 3.2 million tons of wheat and all of Brazil is expected to produce a total of 5.4 million tons compared to 5.0 million tons produced in 2009. Heavy rains during the 2009 harvest reduced the quality of the wheat so much so that nearly half of Parana's 2009 wheat crop was considered only feed quality.
		</description>
		<link>
			http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Oct15_10-Currency-Exchange-Rate-Aids-Brazilian-Millers-Import-Wheat
		</link>
		<guid>
			http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Oct15_10-Currency-Exchange-Rate-Aids-Brazilian-Millers-Import-Wheat
		</guid>
	</item>

	<item>
		<title>
		  October 15, 2010: Farm Groups Ask Judges to Stop Repossession of Equipment in Mato Grosso 
        </title>
		<description>
			Farmers in Mato Grosso have until today, October 15th, to renegotiate their outstanding debts with the Bank of Brazil and equipment dealers or face the repossession of the equipment that was purchased with these outstanding loans.  Many of these problematic loans date back to 2003 and 2004 and they have been rolled over several times already.  Each time the loan is rolled over, the total amount of the loan increases while at the same time, the value of the equipment declines.  Even if the equipment is repossessed and sold at auction, the proceeds of the sale would only pay a small portion of the original note leaving the farmer with very few options for paying off the balance.
		</description>
		<link>
			http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Oct15_10-Farm-Groups-Ask-Judges-to-Stop-Repossions-of-Equipment-in-Mato-Grosso
		</link>
		<guid>
			http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Oct15_10-Farm-Groups-Ask-Judges-to-Stop-Repossions-of-Equipment-in-Mato-Grosso
		</guid>
	</item>

	<item>
		<title>
		    October 14, 2010: GMO Soybeans in Brazil Could Reach 80% Market Share in 2010/11
        </title>
		<description>
			Each growing season, GMO soybeans continue to take a larger share of the Brazilian soybean market.  Estimates are that Roundup Ready soybeans could account for as much as 80% of the 2010/11 soybean crop in Brazil.  
		</description>
		<link>
			http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Oct14_10-GMO-Soybeans-in-Brazil-Could-Reach-80-Market-Share-in-201011
		</link>
		<guid>
			http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Oct14_10-GMO-Soybeans-in-Brazil-Could-Reach-80-Market-Share-in-201011
		</guid>
	</item>

	<item>
		<title>
		  October 14, 2010: Delayed Start Could Mean Less Safrinha Corn in Mato Grosso 
        </title>
		<description>
			A delayed start to the summer rains in central Brazil has resulted in a slow and uneven start to soybean planting in Mato Grosso.  A delayed start to soybean planting in Mato Grosso doesn't necessarily mean that the eventual soybean yields will be adversely affected, but it does have the potential to adversely affect the <i>safrinha</i> corn crop in the state.  <i>safrinha</i> corn in Mato Grosso is planted after the soybeans are harvested and Mato Grosso has the largest <i>safrinha</i> corn crop in Brazil.  Approximately 95% of all the corn planted in the state is planted after the soybeans are harvested.  The <i>safrinha</i> corn is generally planted in January and February and harvested in late May or June.  For each week that the soybean planting is delayed, that means the planting of the <i>safrinha</i> corn will be delayed as well.  
		</description>
		<link>
			http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Oct14_10-Delayed-Start-Could-Mean-Less-Safrinha-Corn-in-Mato-Grosso
		</link>
		<guid>
			http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Oct14_10-Delayed-Start-Could-Mean-Less-Safrinha-Corn-in-Mato-Grosso
		</guid>
	</item>

	<item>
		<title>
		    October 13, 2010: Rains in Mato Grosso Have Been Less Than 100% Coverage
        </title>
		<description>
			Certainly some good rains have fallen across Mato Grosso over the last week, but unfortunately the rainfall coverage has not been 100%.  In the areas where the rainfall has been less than adequate, farmers will wait until they receive at least 50 to 60 mm of rainfall (two inches or more) before they will commit to full scale soybean planting.  They are concerned that if they plant to quickly without sufficient soil moisture to insure germination and seedling establishment, the soybeans may germinate but then not have enough moisture for the seedlings to survive another dry period.
		</description>
		<link>
			http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Oct13_10-Rains-in-Mato-Gross-Have-Been-Less-Than-100-Coverage
		</link>
		<guid>
			http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Oct13_10-Rains-in-Mato-Gross-Have-Been-Less-Than-100-Coverage
		</guid>
	</item>

	<item>
		<title>
		  October 13, 2010: Transporting Grain in Brazil Four Times More Expensive Than in U.S.
        </title>
		<description>
			The president of the Agricultural Federation of Santa Catarina, Jose Zeferino Pedrozzo, stated that the top priority of the new Brazilian president should be an increase in infrastructure spending.  He feels that a lack of infrastructure development and the resulting high cost of transportation are more important to Brazilian agriculture than foreign trade barriers or foreign subsidies.
		</description>
		<link>
			http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Oct13_10-Transporting-Grain-in-Brazil-Four-Times-More-Expensive-Than-in-US
		</link>
		<guid>
			http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Oct13_10-Transporting-Grain-in-Brazil-Four-Times-More-Expensive-Than-in-US
		</guid>
	</item>


	<item>
		<title>
		    October 12, 2010: A Strong Brazilian Currency and a Weak Dollar Worry Brazilian Farmers
        </title>
		<description>
			Farmers in Brazil not only pay close attention to the soybean price, they also closely monitor the value of the Brazilian currency compared to the U.S. dollar.  They like what they see as far as the prices are concerned, but they do not like what is happening to the exchange rates.
		</description>
		<link>
			http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Oct12_10-A-Strong-Brazilian-Currency-and-a-Weak-Dollar-Worry-Brazilian-Farmers
		</link>
		<guid>
			http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Oct12_10-A-Strong-Brazilian-Currency-and-a-Weak-Dollar-Worry-Brazilian-Farmers
		</guid>
	</item>

	<item>
		<title>
		  October 12, 2010: Brazil Continues to Expand its Fruit Production
        </title>
		<description>
			While Brazil has gained notoriety in recent years for its expansion of grain and livestock production, little attention has been paid to the expansion of fruit production in the country.  Since 1990, Brazilian fruit production has expanded at an average rate of 2.5% per year and Brazil now ranks third in total fruit production behind only China and India.  The tropical climate and extended growing season in Brazil allows Brazilian fruit growers to produce a wide variety of tropical and temperate fruits.
		</description>
		<link>
			http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Oct12_10-Brazil-Continues-to-Expand-its-Fruit-Production
		</link>
		<guid>
			http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Oct12_10-Brazil-Continues-to-Expand-its-Fruit-Production
		</guid>
	</item>


	<item>
		<title>
		    October 11, 2010: Brazilian Farmers Still Struggling to Retire Old Debts
        </title>
		<description>
			Even though rains have returned to central Brazil and commodity prices are strengthening, many farmers in Mato Grosso are still trying to dig themselves out of debts they incurred years ago.  In fact, there are recent reports of planters and tractors being repossessed by banks and manufactures at the very time that the farmers have started to plant their 2010/11 crops.
		</description>
		<link>
			http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Oct11_10-Brazilian-Farmers-Still-Struggling-to-Retire-Old-Debts
		</link>
		<guid>
			http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Oct11_10-Brazilian-Farmers-Still-Struggling-to-Retire-Old-Debts
		</guid>
	</item>

	<item>
		<title>
		  October 11, 2010: Brazilian Farmers Expanding Cotton Acreage 22% to 29%
        </title>
		<description>
			Farmers in Mato Grosso, the leading cotton producing state in Brazil, are anxious to take advantage of some of the highest cotton prices in ten years by greatly increasing their cotton acreage.  Surveys have indicated that Mato Grosso farmers intend to increase their 2010/11 cotton acreage by 30% compared to 2009/10.  During the last growing season, farmers in Mato Grosso planted 420,000 hectares of cotton and that is expected to increase to 520,000 hectares in 2010/11.  Nationwide, Conab is expecting that Brazilian farmers will plant 1.01 to 1.07 million hectares of cotton, which would be 22% to 29% more than the cotton acreage planted in Brazil in 2009/10.
		</description>
		<link>
			http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Oct11_10-Brazilian-Farmers-Expanding-Cotton-Acreage-22-to-29
		</link>
		<guid>
			http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Oct11_10-Brazilian-Farmers-Expanding-Cotton-Acreage-22-to-29
		</guid>
	</item>

	<item>
		<title>
		    October 8, 2010: Conab Estimates Declines in Soy and Corn Production in 2010/11
        </title>
		<description>
			After a year of record grain production in Brazil in 2009/10, Conab released their first evaluation of the 2010/11 growing season on Thursday indicating that the total Brazilian grain production in 2010/11 will be slightly less than in 2009/10.  The total grain acreage in 2010/11 is estimated at between 47.3 to 48.0 million hectares compared to the 47.3 million hectares planted in 2009/10.  Total grain production is estimated at between 145.7 to 147.9 million tons compared to the record production of 148.8 achieved in 2009/10, or a reduction of 1 to 3 million tons.
		</description>
		<link>
			http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Oct8_10-Conab-Estimates-Declines-in-Soy-and-Corn-Production-in-201011
		</link>
		<guid>
			http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Oct8_10-Conab-Estimates-Declines-in-Soy-and-Corn-Production-in-201011
		</guid>
	</item>

	<item>
		<title>
		  October 8, 2010: High Natural Gas Prices Could Impact Fertilizer Production
        </title>
		<description>
			The goal of the Brazilian government to be self sufficient in fertilizer production within a decade has hit a setback due to the high price of natural gas flowing into Brazil from Bolivia.  The developers of several new nitrogen fertilizer plants that would use the Bolivian gas to produce nitrogen fertilizers, have indicate that the current prices for natural gas have them reconsidering other options.
		</description>
		<link>
			http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Oct8_10-High-Natural-Gas-Prices-Could-Impact-Fertilizer-Production
		</link>
		<guid>
			http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Oct8_10-High-Natural-Gas-Prices-Could-Impact-Fertilizer-Production
		</guid>
	</item>

	<item>
		<title>
		 October 7, 2010: Agriculture Accounts for 25% of Brazil's Grosso Domestic Product
        </title>
		<description>
			According to the Brazilian Institute of Geography and Statistics (IBGE), in 2009, the agricultural sector in Brazil accounted for 25% of the country's Gross Domestic Product as well as one third of the jobs and 42% of Brazil's exports.
		</description>
		<link>
			http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Oct7_10-Agriculture-Accounts-for-25-of-Brazils-Gross-Domestic-Product
		</link>
		<guid>
			http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Oct7_10-Agriculture-Accounts-for-25-of-Brazils-Gross-Domestic-Product
		</guid>
	</item>

	<item>
		<title>
		  October 7, 2010: Crops in the State of Sao Paulo Benefit from Recent Rains
        </title>
		<description>
			In many areas of the state of Sao Paulo, the recent rains have been sufficient enough to recharge the soil moisture and allow farmers to start planting the 2010/11 summer crops.  The heaviest rains were recorded in the western part of the state where 242 mm (9.6 inches) fell in Presidente Prudente and 140 mm (5.6 inches) fell in Jaboticabal.  In these areas, the soil moisture is at 100% capacity, at least for the time being.  Most of the soil moisture across the state is at 50% to 90% capacity with a few locations still at only 10% of capacity.
		</description>
		<link>
			http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Oct7_10-Crops-in-State-of-Sao-Paulo-Benefit-From-Recent-Rains
		</link>
		<guid>
			http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Oct7_10-Crops-in-State-of-Sao-Paulo-Benefit-From-Recent-Rains
		</guid>
	</item>


	<item>
		<title>
		  October 6, 2010: Recent Rains End Prolonged Dry Season in Much of Brazil 
        </title>
		<description>
			Rains fell across much of southern and central Brazil over this past week and as a result, planting of the 2010/11 summer crops is now under way.  Not everyone got enough rain to declare that the dry season has ended especially in eastern Mato Grosso, northern Goias and western Bahia, but the soil moisture has been recharged enough in most of the principal production areas to encourage farmers to start planting.  More rain is forecasted for this week, so the situation should continue improving.  Below are listed the three major agricultural states in Brazil and the planting progress in each state.
		</description>
		<link>
			http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Oct6_10-Recent-Rains-End-Prolonged-Dry-Season-in-Much-of-Brazil
		</link>
		<guid>
			http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Oct6_10-Recent-Rains-End-Prolonged-Dry-Season-in-Much-of-Brazil
		</guid>
	</item>

	<item>
		<title>
		  October 6, 2010: Farmers in Mato Grosso Actively Forward Selling Their Soybeans
        </title>
		<description>
			Even though the rains in Brazil did not start until the last few days of September, farmers in Mato Grosso took advantage of the improved prices to forward contract a lot of the anticipated 2010/11 soybean production.  As of the end of September, 36% of the 2010/11 soybean crop in Mato Grosso had already been contracted compared to 22% last year at this time.
		</description>
		<link>
			http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Oct6_10-Farmers-in-Mato-Grosso-Actively-Forward-Selling-Their-Soybeans
		</link>
		<guid>
			http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Oct6_10-Farmers-in-Mato-Grosso-Actively-Forward-Selling-Their-Soybeans
		</guid>
	</item>

	<item>
		<title>
			October 5, 2010: Corn Ethanol Production Being Proposed for Mato Grosso
		</title>
		<description>
			Farmers in Mato Grosso are searching for a way to use their corn production without having to pay the ultra high transportation costs needed to move their corn out of the state.  For several years, the farmers in the state have suffered through a lack of storage space for their corn, cash prices that are below the coast of production, and elevated transportation costs.  One suggested alternative to transporting the corn to livestock producers in southern Brazil is to use the corn to produce ethanol which can be consumed within the state.  
		</description>
		<link>
			http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Oct5_10-Corn-Ethanol-Production-Being-Proposed-for-Mato-Grosso
		</link>
		<guid>
			http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Oct5_10-Corn-Ethanol-Production-Being-Proposed-for-Mato-Grosso
		</guid>
	</item>

	<item>
		<title>
		  October 4, 2010: Palm Oil Promoted as Alternative to Soy Oil for Biodiesel
        </title>
		<description>
			According to Manoel Bertone, the Brazilian minister in charge of agro-energy production, the Brazilian production of biodiesel fuel should increase 50% in 2010 compared to 2009 to 2.4 billion liters.  He made these comments last week at a meeting held in Buenos Aires attended by other renewable energy experts from Argentina, Chile, Paraguay, and Uruguay.
		</description>
		<link>
			http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Oct4_10-Palm-Oil-Promoted-as-Alternative-to-Soy-Oil-for-Biodiesel
		</link>
		<guid>
			http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Oct4_10-Palm-Oil-Promoted-as-Alternative-to-Soy-Oil-for-Biodiesel
		</guid>
	</item>

	<item>
		<title>
			October 4, 2010: Dry Weather Accelerates the Brazilian Wheat Harvest
		</title>
		<description>
			The extended dry season in Brazil caused many problems for Brazilian farmers, but for the wheat growers in southern Brazil, the dry weather has resulted in rapid pace for the wheat harvest and high quality grain.  Farmers in Parana have harvested 60% of their wheat, which is 25% more than what was harvested on October 1, of 2009.  The quality of the wheat being harvested is also vastly superior to last year.  In 2009 heavy rains during October lowered the yield and the quality of the crop to such an extent that half of the wheat harvested in Parana last year was only of feed quality.
		</description>
		<link>
			http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Oct4_10-Dry-Weather-Accelerates-the-Brazilian-Wheat-Harvest
		</link>
		<guid>
			http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Oct4_10-Dry-Weather-Accelerates-the-Brazilian-Wheat-Harvest
		</guid>
	</item>

	<item>
		<title>
		  October 1, 2010: Farmers in Bahia to Plant More Cotton and Soybeans but Less Corn
        </title>
		<description>
			Brazilian farmers in the <i>cerrado</i> region of western Bahia intend to take advantage of high cotton and soybean prices by increasing their 2010/11 cotton and soybean acreages and reducing their corn acreage.
		</description>
		<link>
			http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Oct1_10-Farmers-in-Bahia-Plant-More-Cotton-and-Soybeans-but-Less-Corn
		</link>
		<guid>
			http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Oct1_10-Farmers-in-Bahia-Plant-More-Cotton-and-Soybeans-but-Less-Corn
		</guid>
	</item>

	<item>
		<title>
			October 1, 2010: Canola Harvest Starts in Southern Brazil
		</title>
		<description>
			The production of canola in Brazil has been slowly increasing in recent years as farmers look for an alternative to wheat production as well as a new source of vegetable oil for biodiesel production.  According to Conab, slightly more than 46,000 hectares of canola were planted in southern Brazil in 2010 with Rio Grande do Sul being the principal state producing 66% of Brazil's total production.
		</description>
		<link>
			http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Oct1_10-Canola-Harvest-Starts-in-Southern-Brazil
		</link>
		<guid>
			http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Oct1_10-Canola-Harvest-Starts-in-Southern-Brazil
		</guid>
	</item>

	<item>
		<title>
		  September 30, 2010: Presidential Elections to be Held in Brazil on October 3rd
        </title>
		<description>
			Presidential elections will be held in Brazil next Sunday, October 3.  The leading candidate is Ms. Dilma Rousseff, who was Chief of Staff for President Luiz Inacio Lula da Silva.  Her principal opponent is Mr. Jose Serra the former governor of the state of Sao Paulo.  In recent polling, Rousseff has been leading with more than the 50% needed to win in the first round of voting.
		</description>
		<link>
			http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Sept30_10-Presidential-Election-to-be-Held-in-Brazil-in-October-3
		</link>
		<guid>
			http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Sept30_10-Presidential-Election-to-be-Held-in-Brazil-in-October-3
		</guid>
	</item>

	<item>
		<title>
			September 30, 2010: Lower Seed Sales Indicate Reduced Full Season Corn Acreage in Brazil
		</title>
		<description>
			The extended dry season in Brazil has had an effect on the anticipated 2010/11 full season corn acreage in the country.  In the Brazilian states where the corn is planted earlier (late August through September), such as Parana and Rio Grande do Sul, farmers are reducing their full season corn acreage while in states where planting occurs later, such as Minas Gerais, farmers are increasing their full season corn acreage.  The net result though is going to be a 10% to 15% reduction in Brazil's full season corn acreage.  
		</description>
		<link>
			http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Sept30_10-Lower-Seed-Sale-Indicate-Reduced-Full-Season-Corn-Acreage-in-Brazil
		</link>
		<guid>
			http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Sept30_10-Lower-Seed-Sale-Indicate-Reduced-Full-Season-Corn-Acreage-in-Brazil
		</guid>
	</item>

	<item>
		<title>
		  September 29, 2010: Rains Return - Planting Begins in Southern Brazil
        </title>
		<description>
			Over the weekend, summer rains returned to parts of central Brazil for the first time since April.  Heavy and widespread rains fell in Mato Grosso do Sul with only scattered rains falling in Mato Grosso and Goias (at least for the time being).  The forecast is calling for more widespread rains to fall across much of central Brazil during this week.  In southern Brazil, there were also widespread rains in Rio Grande do Sul, Parana, and Sao Paulo as well.
		</description>
		<link>
			http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Sept29_10-Rains-Return-Planting-Begins-in-Southern-Brazil
		</link>
		<guid>
			http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Sept29_10-Rains-Return-Planting-Begins-in-Southern-Brazil
		</guid>
	</item>

	<item>
		<title>
			September 29, 2010: Flooding In Minnesota Could Lower U.S. Corn Yield
		</title>
		<description>
			Minnesota floods - The extensive heavy rains and flooding that occurred over much of southern Minnesota last week is going to result in crop losses throughout the region.  Tens of thousands of acres of corn and soybeans (the total extent of the damage is not yet known) were flooded.  In the hardest hit areas, it could be weeks before the farmers will be able to get into their fields to begin harvesting.  Even in areas where the damage was less severe, it will take a week of good drying weather to firm up the soils enough for harvesting to commence.
		</description>
		<link>
			http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Sept29_10-Flooding-in-Minnesota-Could-Lower-US-Corn-Yield
		</link>
		<guid>
			http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Sept29_10-Flooding-in-Minnesota-Could-Lower-US-Corn-Yield
		</guid>
	</item>

	<item>
		<title>
		  September 28, 2010: Rains End Dry Season in Southern Brazil
        </title>
		<description>
			Heavy rains have been falling in southern Brazil since late last week and they are expected to continue in the region this week as well.  In many areas these are the first rains since April and they mark the end of Brazil's extended 2010 dry season.
		</description>
		<link>
			http://127.0.0.1:5000/news/Sept28_10-Rains-End-Dry-Season-in-Southern-Brazil
		</link>
		<guid>
			http://127.0.0.1:5000/news/Sept28_10-Rains-End-Dry-Season-in-Southern-Brazil
		</guid>
	</item>

	<item>
		<title>
			September 28, 2010: Extended Dry Season Impacted Livestock in Central Brazil
		</title>
		<description>
			Most of the news from Brazil has focused on the lack of rain and the delayed start to the planting season, but the heat and dry weather also took a toll on livestock producers in central Brazil as well.  Beef, swine, and poultry producers all reported that the exceptionally high temperatures and lack of rainfall have adversely affected their operations.
		</description>
		<link>
			http://127.0.0.1:5000/news/Sept28_10-Extended-Dry-Season-Impacted-Livestock-in-Central-Brazil
		</link>
		<guid>
			http://127.0.0.1:5000/news/Sept28_10-Extended-Dry-Season-Impacted-Livestock-in-Central-Brazil
		</guid>
	</item>

	<item>
		<title>
		  September 27, 2010: Brazilian Government Aims to Blunt Increasing Corn Prices
        </title>
		<description>
			For most of 2010, the federal government in Brazil had been concerned about low domestic corn prices and the fact that the cash prices in the interior of the country were below the cost of production, but in recent months, the situation has changed completely.  Due to the drought in Russia and the subsequent increase in international corn prices, now the government is concerned about rising corn prices and their effect on livestock producers in southern Brazil.
		</description>
		<link>
			http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Sept27_10-Brazilian-Government-Aims-to-Blunt-Increasing-Corn-Prices
		</link>
		<guid>
			http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Sept27_10-Brazilian-Government-Aims-to-Blunt-Increasing-Corn-Prices
		</guid>
	</item>

	<item>
		<title>
			September 27, 2010: Framers in Brazil Aggressively Forward Selling Their 2010/11 Crop
		</title>
		<description>
			Even though most farmers in Mato Grosso are just now beginning to plant their 2010/11 soybean crop, they have already been actively forward selling their anticipated soybean crop to take advantage of the stronger prices.  According the Mato Grosso Institute of Agricultural Economics (Imea), approximately 37% of the 2010/11 soybean crop has already been priced compared to last year when 22.5% of the crop had been priced at the same time.
		</description>
		<link>
			http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Sept27_10-Farmers-in-Brazil-Aggresively-Forward-Selling-Their-201011-Crop
		</link>
		<guid>
			http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Sept27_10-Farmers-in-Brazil-Aggresively-Forward-Selling-Their-201011-Crop
		</guid>
	</item>

	<item>
		<title>
			September 23, 2010: Mato Grosso Continues to Endure a Relentless Dry Season
        </title>
		<description>
			We have heard a lot recently about how the extended dry season in central Brazil has delayed the start of soybean planting, but the dry weather also continues to take a toll on the residents and livestock of Mato Grosso.  Last Thursday, the temperature in Cuiaba, the capital of Mato Grosso, reached 41.9 C (108 F), which is the highest temperature recorded anywhere in Brazil during 2010.  This temperature was only 0.3 C shy of the all-time record for Cuiaba, which is 42.1 C (109 F) set 61 years ago in 1949.  
		</description>
		<link>
			http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Sept23_10-Mato-Grosso-Continues-to-Endure-a-Relentless-Dry-Season
		</link>
		<guid>
			http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Sept23_10-Mato-Grosso-Continues-to-Endure-a-Relentless-Dry-Season
		</guid>
	</item>

	<item>
		<title>
			September 23, 2010: Ethanol Production in Brazil Concentrated in Hands of a Few
		</title>
		<description>
			Ethanol production in Brazil continues to become more concentrated in the hands of the largest proucers.  In the year 2000, the largest ethanol producers accounted for 25% of Brazil's total ethanol production.  By the 2009/10 growing season, the seven largest producers accounted for 61% of Brazil's ethanol production and by the end of the 2010/11 growing season, the same seven groups will account for 67% of the total ethanol production in Brazil.  This concentration has been the result of relentless mergers and acquisitions over the last decade.
		</description>
		<link>
			http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Sept23_10-Ethanol-Production-in-Brazil-to-Endure-Relentless-Dry-Season
		</link>
		<guid>
			http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Sept23_10-Ethanol-Production-in-Brazil-to-Endure-Relentless-Dry-Season
		</guid>
	</item>

	<item>
		<title>
			September 22, 2010: Initial Soybean Planting Delayed at Least Three Weeks in Brazil
        </title>
		<description>
			Farmers in Mato Grosso feel the summer planting may be delayed at least three weeks compared to last year.  In most regions of the state it has not rained since early April and the soil is hot, the sun is intense, the temperatures are extreme, and the relative humidity is low.  No one will plant under these conditions unless they have irrigation available.
		</description>
		<link>
			http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Sept22_10-Initial-Soybean-Planting-Delayed-at-Least-Three-Weeks-in-Brazil
		</link>
		<guid>
			http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Sept22_10-Initial-Soybean-Planting-Delayed-at-Least-Three-Weeks-in-Brazil
		</guid>
	</item>

	<item>
		<title>
			September 22, 2010: Full Season Corn Crop in Parana Only 5% Planted
		</title>
		<description>
			Farmers in Parana have been waiting for the first rains of the new growing season to start planting their 2010/11 corn crop.  Fortunately, scattered showers did move across the far southern part of the state yesterday.  Unfortunately, the northern part of the state did not receive any rain and that part of the state has been dry for over two months.
		</description>
		<link>
			http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Sept22_10-Full-Season-Corn-Crop-in-Parana-Only-5-Planted
		</link>
		<guid>
			http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Sept22_10-Full-Season-Corn-Crop-in-Parana-Only-5-Planted
		</guid>
	</item>

	<item>
		<title>
		September 21, 2010: New Urea Factory Planned for the State of Parana
        </title>
		<description>
			A group of co-ops in Parana will announce this week the formation of a new consortium that will build a new urea factory in the state with the capacity of producing 300,000 tons of urea per year.  The total investment is expected to be approximately US$ 300 million and the factory will generate 300 new jobs and hopefully make the state nearly auto sufficient in urea production.
		</description>
		<link>
			http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Sept21_10-New-Urea-Factory-Planned-For-State-of-Parana
		</link>
		<guid>
			http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Sept21_10-New-Urea-Factory-Planned-For-State-of-Parana
		</guid>
	</item>

	<item>
		<title>
		September 20, 2010: Extended Dry Season Impacting Sugarcane Crop in Southern Brazil
		</title>
		<description>
			The extended dry season in Brazil is not only delaying the start of planting the 2010/11 summer crops, it is also impacting the sugarcane crop in southern Brazil as well. The sugarcane tonnage in southern Brazil is expected to be less than anticipated for the second year in a row.
		</description>
		<link>
			http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Sept20_10-Extended-Dry-Season-Impacting-Sugarcane-Crop-in-Southern-Brazil
		</link>
		<guid>
			http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Sept20_10-Extended-Dry-Season-Impacting-Sugarcane-Crop-in-Southern-Brazil
		</guid>
	</item>

	<item>
		<title>
			September 20, 2010: Spring Planting Under Way in Rio Grande do Sul
		</title>
		<description>
			While the summer rains have not yet materialized in central Brazil, there have been ample showers in far southern Brazil to start planting the 2010/11 summer crops.  After a relatively slow start to planting, farmers in Rio Grande do Sul are now actively planting their 2010/11 corn and dry bean crops.  Some of the earlier planted corn in northwestern Rio Grande do Sul will need to be replanted due to poor germination, but the vast majority of the corn crop is expected to have adequate germination and stand establishment.
		</description>
		<link>
			http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Sept20_10-Spring-Planting-Under-Way-in-Rio-Grande-do-Sul
		</link>
		<guid>
			http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Sept20_10-Spring-Planting-Under-Way-in-Rio-Grande-do-Sul
		</guid>
	</item>


	<item>
		<title>
		September 16, 2010: Mato Grosso Farmers May Now Start Planting Soybeans 
		</title>
		<description>
			The 90-day soybean free period in Mato Grosso has now ended and farmers may start planting their 2010/11 soybean crop if the local conditions are right.  This prohibition period, which has been in place for five years, was designed to slow the early spread of soybean rust into newly planted soybean fields.  Live soybean plants are prohibited in the state between June 15th and September 15th.
		</description>
		<link>
			http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Sept16_10-Mato-Grosso-Farmers-May-Now-Start-Planting-Soybeans
		</link>
		<guid>
			http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Sept16_10-Mato-Grosso-Farmers-May-Now-Start-Planting-Soybeans
		</guid>
	</item>

	<item>
		<title>
			September 16, 2010: Brazilian Farmers Expected to Cut Back on Full Season Corn Acreage
		</title>
		<description>
			Only two states in Brazil, Sao Paulo and Minas Gerais, are expected to maintain their corn acreage for the 2010/11 growing season and there is an outside chance that full season corn acreage might actually increase slightly in those two states.  In the remainder of the corn producing states in southern Brazil, the full season corn acreage is expected to decline 15 to 20%.
		</description>
		<link>
			http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Sept16_10-Brazilian-Farmers-Expected-to-Cut-Back-on-Full-Season-Corn-Acreage
		</link>
		<guid>
			http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Sept16_10-Brazilian-Farmers-Expected-to-Cut-Back-on-Full-Season-Corn-Acreage
		</guid>
	</item>

	<item>
		<title>
		September 15, 2010: Brazilians Continue to Switch from Full Season to Safrinha Corn 
		</title>
		<description>
			Farmers in southern Brazil are expected to continue reducing their full season corn acreage in 2010/11 in favor of additional soybean acreage and dry bean acreage.  Even though corn prices have rallied internationally over the last few weeks, it probably has not been enough to convince farmers in southern Brazil to retain all of their full season corn acreage.
		</description>
		<link>
			http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Sept15_10-Brazilians-Continue-to-Switch-From-Full-Season-to-Safrinha-Corn
		</link>
		<guid>
			http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Sept15_10-Brazilians-Continue-to-Switch-From-Full-Season-to-Safrinha-Corn
		</guid>
	</item>

	<item>
		<title>
			September 15, 2010: Dry Weather in Central Brazil Could Delay Soybean Planting
		</title>
		<description>
			Over the past week there have been a few light and widely scattered showers in far western Mato Grosso.  Ninety five percent of central Brazil is still waiting for the first showers of the new growing season.  Temperatures in central Brazil are near 100 degrees and the relative humidity is extremely low.  The air is full of smoke and dust and everyone has their eyes to the skies looking for that first rain.
		</description>
		<link>
			http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Sept15_10-Dry-Weather-in-Central-Brazil-Could-Delay-Soybean-Planting
		</link>
		<guid>
			http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Sept15_10-Dry-Weather-in-Central-Brazil-Could-Delay-Soybean-Planting
		</guid>
	</item>

	<item>
		<title>
			September 14, 2010: Lower Profit Margins for Soy in Mato Grosso Compared to Illinois
		</title>
		<description>
			Soybean farmers in Mato Grosso, Brazil can produce soybeans cheaper than the farmers in Illinois, but they have a smaller profit margin due to the high cost of transporting their soybeans out of the state.  That is the conclusion of the Mato Grosso Institute of Agricultural Economics (Imea) when they compared the cost of producing and transporting soybeans in Illinois and in Mato Grosso.  Mato Grosso soybean farmers spent approximately 12% less to produce their soybeans as compared to farmers in Illinois, but they spent 85% more to transport the soybeans to port facilities.
		</description>
		<link>
			http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Sept14_10-Lower-Profit-Margins-for-Soy-in-Mato-Grosso-Compared-to-Illinois
		</link>
		<guid>
			http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Sept14_10-Lower-Profit-Margins-for-Soy-in-Mato-Grosso-Compared-to-Illinois
		</guid>
	</item>

	<item>
		<title>
		September 14, 2010: Low Water Level on Madeira River Impedes Barge Operations
		</title>
		<description>
			The extended dry season in Brazil is not only worrying farmers in central Brazil, it is also causing disruptions for the only barging operation in the Amazon Region.  Low water levels on the Madeira Rives in the state of Amazonas has forced the Grupo Andre Maggi barging company to cut back on barging operations until the water levels improve.
		</description>
		<link>
			http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Sept14_10-Low-Water-Level-On-Madeira-River-Impedes-Barge-Operations
		</link>
		<guid>
			http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Sept14_10-Low-Water-Level-On-Madeira-River-Impedes-Barge-Operations
		</guid>
	</item>

	<item>
		<title>
			September 13, 2010: The State of Parana Ranks High In Sustainable Agriculture
		</title>
		<description>
			In recent years, there has been a concerted effort in Brazil to make agriculture more sustainable.  Instead of expanding their agricultural base by deforestation in the <i>cerrado</i> and Amazon regions, the government has placed greater emphasis on increasing agricultural production in existing agricultural areas.  Sustainable agriculture involves many factors such as:  reducing deforestation, using less agricultural chemicals, improving soil fertility, reducing soil erosion and a more equitable distribution of rural incomes especially for smaller family farmers.  In all of these areas, the state of Parana has been one of the leaders in Brazil.
		</description>
		<link>
			http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Sept13_10-The-State-of-Parana-Ranks-High-in-Sustainable-Agriculture
		</link>
		<guid>
			http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Sept13_10-The-State-of-Parana-Ranks-High-in-Sustainable-Agriculture
		</guid>
	</item>

	<item>
		<title>
			August 27, 2010: U.S. Soybeans out Performing the Corn Crop
		</title>
		<description>
			As the summer has progressed, the U.S. soybean crop has started to outperform the corn crop.  In contrast to the corn, the soybeans have not been affected nearly as much by the high temperatures.  Additionally, the soybeans make their own nitrogen of course, so the crop has not been affected by the leaching of the nitrogen that occurred with the heavy rains earlier in the summer.
		</description>
		<link>
			http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Aug27_10-US-Soybeans-out-Performing-the-Corn-Crop
		</link>
		<guid>
			http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Aug27_10-US-Soybeans-out-Performing-the-Corn-Crop
		</guid>
	</item>

	<item>
		<title>
			August 27, 2010: U.S. Corn Crop Maturing Too Quickly  
		</title>
		<description>
			Several factors seem to be limiting the corn yield potential this year.  One of the main factors is the high temperatures which have been pushing along the corn development much too fast.  This rapid maturity does not give the plant enough time to slowly fill the kernel.  Instead, the kernels are filled too quickly resulting in potentially smaller kernels that have lighter weights.  This rapid maturity is a concern all across the central and southern Corn Belt. 
		</description>
		<link>
			http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Aug27_10-US-Corn-Crop-Maturing-Too-Quickly
		</link>
		<guid>
			http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Aug27_10-US-Corn-Crop-Maturing-Too-Quickly
		</guid>
	</item>

	<item>
		<title>
			August 26, 2010: Mato Grosso Has Highest Transportation Costs in Brazil
		</title>
		<description>
			Approximately 70% of the grain produced in Mato Grosso moves to the ports by truck, making the state the most expensive location in Brazil to grow soybeans. A lack of alternative modes of transportation has frustrated Mato Grosso soybean farmers ever since soybean production started in the state.  According to the National Association of Cereal Exporters (Anec), the average cost of moving a ton of soybeans from the state to the ports is R$ 230 per ton or US$ 130 per ton.  The cost of moving a ton of grain from the neighboring state of Mato Grosso do Sul to the port is R$ 115 per tons and from the state of Sao Paulo it is just R$ 67 per ton. 
		</description>
		<link>
			http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Aug26_10-Mato-Grosso-Has-Highest-Transportation-Cost-in-Brazil
		</link>
		<guid>
			http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Aug26_10-Mato-Grosso-Has-Highest-Transportation-Cost-in-Brazil
		</guid>
	</item>

	<item>
		<title>
			August 26, 2010: Embrapa Will Increase Development of Conventional Soy in Brazil  
		</title>
		<description>
			Brazilian soybean producers continue to increase the amount of GMO soybeans they plant on their farms, but there is a small and growing percentage of Brazilian producers that want to continue producing conventional soybeans (non GMO).  They feel there will continue to be a niche for conventional soybeans especially among their European customers.  Since the U.S. and Argentina grow GMO soybeans almost exclusively, they feel that Brazil could become the primary supplier of conventional soybeans.  
		</description>
		<link>
			http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Aug26_10-Embrapa-Will-Increase-Development-of-Conventional-Soy-in-Brazil
		</link>
		<guid>
			http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Aug26_10-Embrapa-Will-Increase-Development-of-Conventional-Soy-in-Brazil
		</guid>
	</item>

	<item>
		<title>
			August 25, 2010: Everyone in Central Brazil Waiting for the "Mango Rain"
		</title>
		<description>
			In many areas in central Brazil it's been more than four months without any measurable rainfall.  Normally, central Brazil receives several episodes of light drizzle during the period of May to August, but this year, the light drizzle did not even occur and as a result, everything is extremely dry.  Recent temperatures in southern Mato Grosso have been in the range of 100 degrees and the relatively humidity has been extremely low.  In parts of southern Mato Grosso, river levels are lower this year than any time since 1970 and there is no rain in the near-term forecast.  
		</description>
		<link>
			http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Aug25_10-Everyone-in-Central-Brazil-Waiting-For-the-Mango-Rain
		</link>
		<guid>
			http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Aug25_10-Everyone-in-Central-Brazil-Waiting-For-the-Mango-Rain
		</guid>
	</item>

	<item>
		<title>
			August 24, 2010: Frogeye Leaf Spot is Most Expensive Disease to Hit Argentine Soy  
		</title>
		<description>
			It seems that farmers in the three main soybeans producing countries are very concerned about how fungal diseases are impacting their soybean crop.  In the U.S., the main concern this growing season has been sudden death syndrome especially in Iowa.  In Brazil, the biggest concern continues to be soybean rust, which is found throughout the country.  In Argentina, biggest concern last growing season was a fungal disease called frogeye leaf spot.  Some researchers in Argentina feel that the disease may have reduced Argentina's 2009/10 soybean crop by 4 to 5 million tons and if that was actually the case, it would be the most expensive disease in terms of lost production to have occurred in Argentine soybean fields. 
		</description>
		<link>
			http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Aug24_10-Frogeye-Leaf-Spot-is-Most-Expensive-Diseas-to-Hit-Argentine-Soy
		</link>
		<guid>
			http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Aug24_10-Frogeye-Leaf-Spot-is-Most-Expensive-Diseas-to-Hit-Argentine-Soy
		</guid>
	</item>
	
	<item>
		<title>
			August 24, 2010: Continued Development of La Nina Worries Argentine Farmers
		</title>
		<description>
			Argentine farmers are keeping a close watch on the development of La Nina in the eastern Pacific.  The Australian Bureau of Meteorology predicts that La Nina will persist until at least early 2011, if not longer.  The Climate Prediction Center of NOAA agrees with the Australian prediction.
		</description>
		<link>
			http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Aug24_10-Continued-Development-of-La-Nina-Worries-Argentine-Farmers
		</link>
		<guid>
			http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Aug24_10-Continued-Development-of-La-Nina-Worries-Argentine-Farmers
		</guid>
	</item>


	<item>
		<title>
			August 23, 2010: Early Wheat Harvest Starts in Parana, Prices Remain Depressed
		</title>
		<description>
			According to the Department of Rural Economics, the farmers in Parana have harvested 2% of their 2010 wheat crop.  In some of the most advanced regions, 10% of the crop has been harvested.  Overall yields are expected to be good even though cold weather and frosts did affect the crop in the southern regions of the state.  Certainly this crop will be better than the 2009 crop that was negatively impacted by dry weather. 
		</description>
		<link>
			http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Aug23_10-Early-Wheat-Harveest-Starts-in-Parana-Prices-Remain-Depressed
		</link>
		<guid>
			http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Aug23_10-Early-Wheat-Harveest-Starts-in-Parana-Prices-Remain-Depressed
		</guid>
	</item>
	
	<item>
		<title>
			August 23, 2010: Second Roundtable on Sustainable Palm Oil Prod to Meet in Brazil 
		</title>
		<description>
			Later this week, participants will kick off the Second Latin American Conference and Roundtable on Sustainable Palm Oil Production scheduled for August 25-26 in Belem, Para.  The Roundtable on Sustainable Palm Oil was founded in 2004 with the goal of developing guidelines for sustainable palm oil production around the world.  An estimated 336 participants from 37 countries will join 40 national associations to discuss sustainable production.
		</description>
		<link>
			http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Aug23_10-Second-Roundtable-on-Sustainable-Palm-Oil-Prod-to-Meet-in-Brazil
		</link>
		<guid>
			http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Aug23_10-Second-Roundtable-on-Sustainable-Palm-Oil-Prod-to-Meet-in-Brazil
		</guid>
	</item>

	<item>
		<title>
			August 20, 2010: Domestic Corn Prices Not Encouraging for Brazilian Farmers
		</title>
		<description>
			Domestic corn prices in Brazil have increased 10% over the last 30 days, but that is not enough to encourage Brazilian farmers to plant more corn.  In fact, just the opposite is expected to occur in 2010/11 growing season as farmers in Brazil continue to reduce their full season corn acreage in favor of additional soybean production. 
		</description>
		<link>
			http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Aug20_10-Domestic-Corn-Prices-Not-Encouraging-for-Brazilia-Farmers
		</link>
		<guid>
			http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Aug20_10-Domestic-Corn-Prices-Not-Encouraging-for-Brazilia-Farmers
		</guid>
	</item>
	
	<item>
		<title>
			August 20, 2010: Canola Offers an Alternative for Winter Grain Production in Brazil
		</title>
		<description>
			The principal winter crop grown in southern Brazil is wheat, but wheat production is a hit or miss proposition in southern Brazil due mainly to lower yields caused by potential heavy rains at the time of harvest.  These heavy rains can result in lower yields and poor grain quality.  In recent years, canola has been gaining in popularity as an alternative to wheat due to its low cost of production and the high demand for canola oil.  Brazil currently imports canola oil for the food processing industry, but many Brazilian scientists feel that canola production in Brazil is set to expand significantly.
		</description>
		<link>
			http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Aug20_10-Canola-Offers-an-Alternative-for-Winter-Grain-Prodution-in-Brazil
		</link>
		<guid>
			http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Aug20_10-Canola-Offers-an-Alternative-for-Winter-Grain-Prodution-in-Brazil
		</guid>
	</item>

	<item>
		<title>
			August 19, 2010: U. S. Corn Yields May Decline From August Crop Estimate
		</title>
		<description>
			It was no surprise that last week's August Crop Report indicated large production estimates for both corn and soybeans.  Everything was in place to produce large estimates, but the estimates last week just might end up being the largest of the growing season for the following reasons: 
		</description>
		<link>
			http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Aug19_10-US-Corn-Yields-May-Decline-From-August-Crop-Estimate
		</link>
		<guid>
			http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Aug19_10-US-Corn-Yields-May-Decline-From-August-Crop-Estimate
		</guid>
	</item>
	
	<item>
		<title>
			August 19, 2010: U.S. Soybean Crop Could Finish Strong, But Faces Challenges
		</title>
		<description>
			The situation for the soybean crop is not quite as clear as it is for the corn crop.  Many soybean fields are finishing the growing season in good condition, but they will probably need at least one more good rainfall to insure that all the pods fill properly.  August is the make or break month for soybeans and the August weather has been quite different depending on where you are in the Corn Belt.  The August weather has been stressful in the eastern and southern Corn Belt as well as the mid-South and the Delta. The August weather has generally been beneficial for the soybean crop in the western and northern Corn Belt.  The one major concern for the soybean crop is the widespread appearance of sudden Death Syndrome in Iowa.  Losses from the disease vary from field to field, but in severe cases, it could be as high as 30% to 40% of the potential yield.  The final U.S. soybean yield could either improve or decline for the following reasons:
		</description>
		<link>
			http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Aug19_10-US-Soybean-Crop-Could-Finish-Strong-But-Faces-Challenges
		</link>
		<guid>
			http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Aug19_10-US-Soybean-Crop-Could-Finish-Strong-But-Faces-Challenges
		</guid>
	</item>

	<item>
		<title>
			August 18, 2010: Soybean's Share of Mato Grosso Exports Decreases in 2010
		</title>
		<description>
			During the first six months of 2010, the value of agricultural exports shipped out of the state of Mato Grosso fell 10% compared to the same period in 2009 and 12% compared to 2008.  In fact, the value of June's exports was the lowest in three years.  The principal reason for the decline was the reduced volume and lower prices paid for soybeans, soybean meal, and soybean oil, which accounts for 70% of the state's exports.
		</description>
		<link>
			http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Aug18_10-Soybeans-Share-of-Mato-Grosso-Exports-Decrease-in-2010
		</link>
		<guid>
			http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Aug18_10-Soybeans-Share-of-Mato-Grosso-Exports-Decrease-in-2010
		</guid>
	</item>

	<item>
		<title>
			August 17, 2010: Brazilian Cotton Acreage to Increase in 2010/11
		</title>
		<description>
			Improved cotton prices are encouraging Brazilian farmers in increase their cotton acreage for the 2010/11 growing season.  According the president of the Brazilian Cotton Producers Association, Haroldo Rodrigues da Cunha, Brazilian cotton growers may plant 950,000 hectares of cotton, which would represent an increase of approximately 15% or 120,000 hectares more than the 830,000 hectares that were planted last year.  
		</description>
		<link>
			http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Aug17_10-Brazilian-Cotton-Acreage-to-Increase-in-201011
		</link>
		<guid>
			http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Aug17_10-Brazilian-Cotton-Acreage-to-Increase-in-201011
		</guid>
	</item>

	<item>
		<title>
			August 17, 2010: Manioc Root and Sweet Potatoes Promoted as Ethanol Producers
		</title>
		<description>
			University researchers in Brazil have been looking for alternative sources for feedstock to supply the raw material for the ever expanding ethanol industry in Brazil.  Currently, sugarcane reigns supreme as virtually the only source of feedstock for the industry, but researchers feel other crops might be a better options depending on the environment where it is grown.  
		</description>
		<link>
			http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Aug17_10-MAnioc-Root-and-Sweet-Potatoes-Promoted-as-Ethanol-Producers
		</link>
		<guid>
			http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Aug17_10-MAnioc-Root-and-Sweet-Potatoes-Promoted-as-Ethanol-Producers
		</guid>
	</item>

	<item>
		<title>
			August 16, 2010: Brazilian Government Continues to Assist Brazilian Corn Growers
		</title>
		<description>
			The Brazilian government has spent a lot of money recently trying to support the price of corn for Brazilian farmers.  The principal way they are doing this is through the Pep Program, which is the Premium for Storage of Products.  Conab administers the program and they have held weekly auctions since May where they purchase corn from producers.  The government also conducts another program called the Pepro Program or the Producer's Equalization Payment Program.  Thus far the government has spent R$ 695 million on the Pep Program and R$ 5.9 million on the Pepro program.	
		</description>
		<link>
			http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Aug16_10-Brazilian-Government-Continues-to-Assist-Brazilian-Corn-Growers
		</link>
		<guid>
			http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Aug16_10-Brazilian-Government-Continues-to-Assist-Brazilian-Corn-Growers
		</guid>
	</item>

	<item>
		<title>
			August 16, 2010: Brazilian Government Continues to Assist Brazilian Corn Growers
		</title>
		<description>
			The principal winter crop grown in Rio Grande do Sul is wheat, but the farmers in the state also grow barley and canola during the winter season.  Winter temperatures in Rio Grande so Sul have been very low this year, but the winter small grains seem to have come through it OK. 
		</description>
		<link>
			http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Aug16_10-Winter-Crops-in-Rio-Grande-do-Sul-Little-Affected-by-Cold-Weather
		</link>
		<guid>
			http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Aug16_10-Winter-Crops-in-Rio-Grande-do-Sul-Little-Affected-by-Cold-Weather
		</guid>
	</item>

	<item>
		<title>
			August 13, 2010: Farmers in Parana Pleased With Safrinha Corn Yields
		</title>
		<description>
			After a delay due to wet weather, farmers in Parana are back in the fields harvesting their <i>safrinha</i> corn crop.  They generally are very pleased with this year's yields, but they are not pleased about the domestic price of corn.  In northern Parana where most of the <i>safrinha</i> is grown, yields are being reported in the range of 75 to 90 sacks per hectare or 70 to 83 bushels per acre.  These are very good yields considering that last year's drought impaired crop yielded only 46 bu/ac.
		</description>
		<link>
			http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Aug13_10-Farmers-in-Parana-Pleased-With-Safinha-Corn-Yields
		</link>
		<guid>
			http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Aug13_10-Farmers-in-Parana-Pleased-With-Safinha-Corn-Yields
		</guid>
	</item>

	<item>
		<title>
			August 13, 2010: Low Rice Prices Discourage Producers in Rio Grande do Sul
		</title>
		<description>
			Rice farmers in Rio Grande do Sul suffered yield losses of up to 15% in their 2010/11 rice crop due to excessive rains during planting and now they are encountering additional difficulties due to reduced exports and lower rice prices.  This is certainly not what they had expected after the 2009/10 rice crop came in significantly below expectations.
		</description>
		<link>
			http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Aug13_10-Low-Rice-Prices-Discourage-Producers-in-Rio-Grane-do-Sul
		</link>
		<guid>
			http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Aug13_10-Low-Rice-Prices-Discourage-Producers-in-Rio-Grane-do-Sul
		</guid>
	</item>

	<item>
		<title>
			August 12, 2010: Brazilian Farmers Quickly Adopting GMO Corn Hybrids
		</title>
		<description>
			Brazilian farmers continue to increase the amount of GMO corn hybrids they are planting on their farms.  During the 2009/10 growing season, it is estimated that 32.5% of the corn grown in Brazil was GMO.  For the 2010/11 growing season, which will be planted starting in a month or so, it is estimated that 55% of the corn grown in Brazil will be GMO.  Approximately 43% of the GMO corn in Brazil is insect resistant.  Three and a half percent of the corn hybrids are herbicide resistant and one percent has both insect and herbicide resistance.
		</description>
		<link>
			http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Aug12_10-Brazilian-Farmers-Quickly-Adopting-GMO-Corn-Hybrids
		</link>
		<guid>
			http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Aug12_10-Brazilian-Farmers-Quickly-Adopting-GMO-Corn-Hybrids
		</guid>
	</item>

	<item>
		<title>
			August 12, 2010: Brazilian Scientists Trying to Discover Cause of "Crazy Soybean II"
		</title>
		<description>
			As Brazilian soybean scientists gather this week for their 31st annual Soybean Research Conference in Brasilia, one of the top areas of discussion will be a new phenomenon that has been discovered in Brazilian soybean fields over the last two years called "Crazy Soybean II".  Researchers do not know what is causing the phenomenon, if it is a disease, a virus, a fungus, or if it is caused by insect attacks or environmental conditions.
		</description>
		<link>
			http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Aug12_10-Brazilian-Scientist-Trying-to-Discover-Cause-of-Crazy-Soybean-II
		</link>
		<guid>
			http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Aug12_10-Brazilian-Scientist-Trying-to-Discover-Cause-of-Crazy-Soybean-II
		</guid>
	</item>

	<item>
		<title>
			August 11, 2010: Brazilian Soybean Acreage Estimated to Increase 3-4% in 2010/11
		</title>
		<description>
			The Brazilian soybean acreage is expected to increase 3% to 4% in 2010/11 due to:  improved soybean prices, higher potential returns for soybeans, reduced costs of production, and dismal domestic corn prices in Brazil	
		</description>
		<link>
			http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Aug11_10-Brazilian-Soybean-Acreage-Estimated-to-Increase-3-4-in-201011
		</link>
		<guid>
			http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Aug11_10-Brazilian-Soybean-Acreage-Estimated-to-Increase-3-4-in-201011
		</guid>
	</item>

	<item>
		<title>
			August 11, 2010: Another Antarctic Blast Hits Southern Brazil
		</title>
		<description>
			This has been a winter for the record books with freezing temperatures, heavy frosts, snow falls, icy roads, stranded travelers, frozen fruit trees, and dead cattle, and this has all occurred in southern Brazil!  In the higher elevations of Rio Grande do Sul and Santa Catarina, it snowed again last week for the third time this winter.  As a curious side note, Brazilian tourist flocked to the town of Gramado in Rio Grande do Sul last week in the hope of actually seeing snow.  Gramado, which is located at a higher elevation, is a famous tourist destination in southern Brazil.  If a Brazilian spent his or her entire life in Brazil, the chance of actually seeing snow in Brazil is extremely rare, but this year, it's happened several times already.
		</description>
		<link>
			http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Aug11_10-Another-Antartic-Blast-Hits-Sothern-Brazil
		</link>
		<guid>
			http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Aug11_10-Another-Antartic-Blast-Hits-Sothern-Brazil
		</guid>
	</item>

	<item>
		<title>
			August 10, 2010: Brazilian Gov. Paying a High Price for Aggressive Approach to Ag
		</title>
		<description>
			In recent years the Brazilian government has drastically changed its approach toward the agricultural sector.  After steep increases in food and commodity prices in 2008, there was a concern on the part of the government that continued increases in food costs could led to unrest similar to what was observed in other countries.  In response, the government decided to take a much more proactive approach in building commodity and food stocks in the country in order to avoid any potential shortages.  The goal of the government was to guarantee an abundant and cheap food supply for its citizens.
		</description>
		<link>
			http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Aug10_10-Brazilian-Government-Paying-a-High-Price-for-Aggresive-Approach-To-Ag
		</link>
		<guid>
			http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Aug10_10-Brazilian-Government-Paying-a-High-Price-for-Aggresive-Approach-To-Ag
		</guid>
	</item>

	<item>
		<title>
			August 10, 2010: Waiting to Sell Was the Correct Strategy for Brazilian Soybean Farmers  
		</title>
		<description>
			One of the toughest decisions for any farmer is to decide when to sell their crops.  In Brazil it's no different.  For the last several years, soybean farmers in Brazil have been conditioned to expect some type of weather scare during the U.S. summer growing season that would result in a spike in soybean prices.  This year it happened again, but this time it was poor weather in Eastern Europe instead of North America that did the trick.
		</description>
		<link>
			http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Aug10_10-Waiting-to-Sell-Was-The-Correct-Strategy-For-Brazilian-Soybean-Farmers
		</link>
		<guid>
			http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Aug10_10-Waiting-to-Sell-Was-The-Correct-Strategy-For-Brazilian-Soybean-Farmers
		</guid>
	</item>


	<item>
		<title>
			August 9, 2010: Canola Gaining Foothold as a Safrinha Crop in Brazil
		</title>
		<description>
			Farmers in Brazil are now viewing canola as a viable alternative to corn as a <i>safrinha</i> crop.  Five years ago, the production of canola in Brazil was practically zero.  Today there is approximately 40,000 hectares of canola grown in Brazil and it is increasing rapidly every year.  The largest producing state is Rio Grande do Sul (slightly more than 50% of Brazil's total) followed by Parana (approximately one third of the total) and the crop is even gaining popularity in central Brazil.
		</description>
		<link>
			http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Aug9_10-Canola-Gaining-Foothold-as-a-Safrinha-Crop-in-Brazil
		</link>
		<guid>
			http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Aug9_10-Canola-Gaining-Foothold-as-a-Safrinha-Crop-in-Brazil
		</guid>
	</item>

	<item>
		<title>
			August 9, 2010: 4,700 Hectares of Illegal Soybeans Discovered in Parana 
		</title>
		<description>
			This is the time of year in Brazil when commercial soybean production is prohibited.  The 90-day soybean free period, which started five years ago in Mato Grosso, is used as a way to break the soybean rust disease cycle.  Soybean rust spores cannot survive for more than 60 days without a host plant so the idea is to eliminate soybeans as a host during the dry season.  This practice has worked well in central Brazil and it has been adopted by most soybean growing states in Brazil. 
		</description>
		<link>
			http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Aug9_10-4700-Hectare-of-Illegal-Soybeans-Discovered-in-Parana
		</link>
		<guid>
			http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Aug9_10-4700-Hectare-of-Illegal-Soybeans-Discovered-in-Parana
		</guid>
	</item>

	<item>
		<title>
			August 6, 2010: Brazilian Congress to Make Land Purchases by Foreigners More Difficult
		</title>
		<description>
			The Brazilian government is contemplating measures that would make the purchase of Brazilian farmland by foreign individuals and corporations more difficult and more transparent.  One of the key provisions of the proposed regulations is to require the purchase process be approved by Incra before it can move forward.  Incra, which is the National Institute of Colonization and Agrarian Reform, is the agency most heavily involved in land acquisitions in Brazil. 
		</description>
		<link>
			http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Aug6-10-Brazilian-Congress-to-Make-Land-Purchaeses-by-Foreigners-More-Difficult
		</link>
		<guid>
			http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Aug6-10-Brazilian-Congress-to-Make-Land-Purchaeses-by-Foreigners-More-Difficult
		</guid>
	</item>

	<item>
		<title>
			August 6, 2010: Brazilian Farmers Are Aggressively Purchasing Inputs for 2010/11 Crops
		</title>
		<description>
			Even though temperatures have been very cold in southern Brazil and current soybean prices in Brazil are lower than they were last year at this time, Brazilian farmers have been aggressively purchasing the needed inputs for their 2010/11 crops.  Data released by the Brazilian National Association of Fertilizer Distributors indicate that during the first half of 2010 Brazilian farmers took delivery of 4.2% more fertilizer than during the same period in 2009.  The fertilizer distributors have already delivered 8.62 million tons of fertilizers for all types of crops compared to 8.27 million tons delivered during the first half of 2009.
		</description>
		<link>
			http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Aug6_10-Brazilian-Farmers-Are-Aggressively-Purchasing-Inputs-for-201011-Crops
		</link>
		<guid>
			http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Aug6_10-Brazilian-Farmers-Are-Aggressively-Purchasing-Inputs-for-201011-Crops
		</guid>
	</item>

	<item>
		<title>
			August 5, 2010: Trip report - Iowa, Central Illinois and Western Indiana
		</title>
		<description>
			<b>Iowa</b> - On July 31st I traveled across Iowa from east to west in the northern part of the state and then from west to east across the central part of the state.  I calculated the corn yield in a dozen different fields across the state.  This was not a scientific sampling by any stretch of the imagination because I had to avoid the worse areas where there was standing water.  What I tried to do was to choose average looking corn fields.  Below are my observations.
		</description>
		<link>
			http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Aug5_10-Trip-Report-Iowa-Central-Illinois-and-Western-Indiana
		</link>
		<guid>
			http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Aug5_10-Trip-Report-Iowa-Central-Illinois-and-Western-Indiana
		</guid>
	</item>

	<item>
		<title>
			August 5, 2010: Brazilian Ports Working to Get Bigger Share of Paraguay Grain Exports
		</title>
		<description>
			Port authorities at the Ports of Paranagua and Antonina located in the state of Parana are working with co-op officials in land-locked Paraguay to establish a "dry port" in western Parana for the export of soybeans, soybean meal, corn, and wheat grown in Paraguay.  The Port of Paranagua used to be the principal port for exports out of Paraguay, but the Brazilian ports have lost business in recent years to ports in Uruguay and Argentina located downstream from Paraguay on the Parana River.
		</description>
		<link>
			http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Aug5_10-Brazilian-Porks-Workging-To-Get-Bigger-Share-of-Paraguay-Grain-Exports
		</link>
		<guid>
			http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Aug5_10-Brazilian-Porks-Workging-To-Get-Bigger-Share-of-Paraguay-Grain-Exports
		</guid>
	</item>

	<item>
		<title>
			August 5, 2010: Brazilian Agronomist Explain Strategies to Combat Potential Dry Weather 
		</title>
		<description>
			With reports that the developing La Nina may be more intense than the last one during the 2007/08 growing season, agronomist in southern Brazil are already advising their farmer clients on strategies to help minimize any potential adverse affects of the dry weather might have on their 2010/11 crops. A La Nina generally results in dryer than normal weather in southern Brazil during the spring and early summer (September to December) and eventually lower yields.
		</description>
		<link>
			http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Aug5_10-Brazilian-Agronomist-Explain-Stratagies-to-Combat-Potential-Dry-Weather
		</link>
		<guid>
			http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Aug5_10-Brazilian-Agronomist-Explain-Stratagies-to-Combat-Potential-Dry-Weather
		</guid>
	</item>


	<item>
		<title>
			August 3, 2010: Brazilian Meteorologists Predict Dry Spring in Southern Brazil
		</title>
		<description>
			Meteorologists in Brazil are already warning farmers in southern Brazil to expect a dryer than normal spring planting season which will start later this month.  Gilberto Diniz from the Federal University of Pelotas, which is located in the southern part of Rio Grande do Sul, predicts that the transiting into a La Nina in the eastern Pacific will result in below normal rainfall in southern Brazil starting by the end of September.  The dryer than normal pattern is expected to persist until at least the end of 2010.
		</description>
		<link>
			http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Aug3_10-Brazilian-Meteorologists-Predict-Dry-Spring-in-Southern-Brazil
		</link>
		<guid>
			http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Aug3_10-Brazilian-Meteorologists-Predict-Dry-Spring-in-Southern-Brazil
		</guid>
	</item>


	<item>
		<title>
			August 3, 2010: First Corn Ethanol Plant to be Inaugurated in Mato Grosso
		</title>
		<description>
			In a country that leads the world in ethanol produced from sugarcane, the farmers in Mato Grosso are trying to chart a new path by opening their first ethanol plant that uses corn instead of sugarcane to produce ethanol.  The Association of Soybean and Corn Producers of Mato Grosso in association with Embrapa, are scheduled to open their first experimental corn ethanol plant this week.
		</description>
		<link>
			http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Aug3_10-First-Corn-Ethanol-Plant-to-be-Inaugurated-in-Mato-Grosso
		</link>
		<guid>
			http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Aug3_10-First-Corn-Ethanol-Plant-to-be-Inaugurated-in-Mato-Grosso
		</guid>
	</item>

<item>
<title>
	August 2, 2010: India Could Become the "New China" For Latin American Exports
</title>
<description>
	According to a study released by the Interamerican Development Bank (BID), India is now poised to become the new destination of Latin American exports similar to what happened with China during the past decade.  With more than a billion people and a growth rate of 6.5 to 8% over the last decade, Latin American businesses feel that India will become the new area of growth for their exports.
</description>
<link>
	http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Aug2_10-India-Could-Become-the-New-China-For-Latin-Exports
</link>
<guid>
	http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Aug2_10-India-Could-Become-the-New-China-For-Latin-Exports
</guid>
</item>


<item>
<title>
	August 2, 2010: Brazilian Corn Exports Accelerate Due to European Demand
</title>
<description>
	The ongoing drought in Eastern Europe has European importers looking more toward Brazil for needed supplies of corn.  The severe reduction in wheat and corn production has livestock feeders scrambling to secure needed feed supplies.  Brazil is a logical source because of the low percentage of Brazilian farmers who grow GMO corn. 
</description>
<link>
	http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Aug2_10-Brazilian-Corn-Exports-Accelerated-Due-to-European-Demand
</link>
<guid>
	http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Aug2_10-Brazilian-Corn-Exports-Accelerated-Due-to-European-Demand
</guid>
</item>



<item>
<title>
	July 30, 2010: Illegal Fires Detected in Sao Paulo Sugarcane Fields
</title>
<description>
	Agricultural officials in the state of Sao Paulo have been working hard over the last several years to eliminate the practice of burning the sugarcane prior to harvesting.  Burning off the sugarcane leaves is an age-old practice that has been common in Brazil for hundreds of years.  The leaves are burned off in order to facilitate the harvesting of the cane by hand.  The problem is that the burning greatly adds to the amount of pollution in the air as well as increasing the amount of greenhouse gas emissions from the sugarcane fields.
</description>
<link>
	http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Jul30_10-Illegal-Fires-Detected-in-Sao-Paulo-Sugarcane-Fields
</link>
<guid>
	http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Jul30_10-Illegal-Fires-Detected-in-Sao-Paulo-Sugarcane-Fields
</guid>
</item>


<item>
<title>
	July 30, 2010: Cellulosic Ethanol Production Focus of Research Efforts in Brazil
</title>
<description>
	The Center for Sugarcane Technology (CTC) located in Piracicaba, Sao Paulo, is marking its fifth anniversary as an independent research organization focused on improved sugarcane production and processing.  Started in 1969 by Copersucar, the center was a part of the company until 2004 when it became its own entity supported by affiliated companies.  Today, it is supported by 160 different sugarcane producing/processing companies that represent 60% of the sugarcane processed in Brazil.  The center is also associated with 12,000 farmers who grow sugarcane in Brazil.
</description>
<link>
	 http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Jul30_10-Cellulosic-Ethanol-Production-Focus-of-Research-Efforts-in-Brazil
</link>
<guid>
	http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Jul30_10-Cellulosic-Ethanol-Production-Focus-of-Research-Efforts-in-Brazil
</guid>
</item>

<item>
<title>
	July 29, 2010: Soybeans Could Replace Some Full Season Corn in Southern Brazil
</title>
<description>
	The Agriculture Confederation of Brazil (CNA) anticipates that farmers in southern Brazil will once again opt to reduce their full season corn acreage in favor of increased soybean acreage for the 2010/11 growing season.  During the 2009/10 growing season, farmers in southern Brazil reduced their full season corn acreage by 20% while at the same time they increased their soybean acreage by 7.8%.  In southern Brazil, soybeans and full season corn compete for the same acreage since they are planted at the same time.
</description>
<link>
	http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Jul29_10-Soybeans-Replace-Some-Full-Season-Corn-in-Southern-Brazil
</link>
<guid>
	http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Jul29_10-Soybeans-Replace-Some-Full-Season-Corn-in-Southern-Brazil
</guid>
</item>


<item>
<title>
	July 29, 2010: Millet Seen As Alternative to Corn for Safrinha Production
</title>
<description>
	The discovery of soybean rust in Brazil during the 2000/10 growing season nixed farmers plans of growing two crops of soybeans in the same field during the same growing season.  Since that time, farmers in central Brazil have been experimenting with other crops that could be grown after the soybeans are harvested.  The principal crop thus far used for this <i>safrinha</i> production has been corn, but other crops such as cotton, sorghum, and millet are starting to gain a foothold.
</description>
<link>
	 http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Jul29_10-Millet-Seen-as-Alternative-to-Corn-for-Safrinha-Production
</link>
<guid>
	http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Jul29_10-Millet-Seen-as-Alternative-to-Corn-for-Safrinha-Production
</guid>
</item>

<item>
<title>
	July 28, 2010: High Temps Increases Dark Respiration in U.S. Corn, Which Could Limit Yields
</title>
<description>
	High daytime and nighttime temperatures can put stress on corn plants that could limit the yield potential of the plant.  The sugars produced by the corn plant during photosynthesis are used by the plant for cell growth, but they are also consumed by the plant at night during a process called dark respiration.  There are two types of dark respiration, the first of which is for cell growth and cellular expansion.  The second type of dark respiration is for cellular maintenance, which is the energy needed to keep the cells alive.  If you take the sugars produced during photosynthesis and subtract the sugars consumed during dark respiration, what is left over are the sugars that the plant stores in the form of carbohydrates which are used later for grain fill.  If too much of the sugars are consumed for dark respiration, then there are less sugars left over for grain filling.
</description>
<link>
	http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Jul28_10-High-Temps-Increases-Dark-Respiration-in-US-Corn-Which-Could-Limit-Yields
</link>
<guid>
	http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Jul28_10-High-Temps-Increases-Dark-Respiration-in-US-Corn-Which-Could-Limit-Yields
</guid>
</item>

<item>
<title>
	July 28, 2010: Improved Soy Prices during July Spur Forward Selling in Brazil
</title>
<description>
	Brazilian soybean farmers always watch the U.S. soybean market very closely during the month of July because that is when concerns about the U.S. weather can cause soybean prices to strengthen.  July usually offers one of the best opportunities for Brazilian to sell their soybeans and it happened again this year.  The March 2011 contract started out the month of July at US$ 9.22 a bushel and peaked several weeks later at about US$ 9.90 a bushel.  This was enough of an increase to convince many Brazilian soybean farmers to sell the remaining 2009/10 production and to forward contract some of their 2010/11 anticipated production. 
</description>



<item>
<title>
July 27, 2010: Few Volunteer Soybeans Found During Soybean-free Period in Brazil
</title>
<description>
State inspectors in Mato Grosso have indicated that there have been few problems thus far in maintaining the 90-day soybean free period in the state.  The program, which was initiated four years ago, requires that no live soybean plants are permitted in the state between June 15th and September 15th, unless they are for pre-approved scientific research.  This includes volunteer soybeans that may germinate in the field, along the side of the road, or in the vicinity of grain handling equipment.
</description>
<link>
http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Jul27_10-Few-Volunteer-Soybeans-Found-During-Soybean-free-Period-in-Brazil
</link>
<guid>
http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Jul27_10-Few-Volunteer-Soybeans-Found-During-Soybean-free-Period-in-Brazil
</guid>
</item>


<item>
<title>
July 27, 2010: Dry Weather Reduces Estimates of Brazil's Sugarcane Production
</title>
<description>
Dry weather in southeastern Brazil has lead to lower estimates for the amount of sugarcane that will be processed during the 2010/11 growing season.  The early end to the rainy season last April resulted in some areas in southeastern Brazil going without rain for up to 130 days.  The dry weather is also expected to result in lower sucrose content of the sugarcane that is harvested during the last half of the growing season that will end in December.
</description>
<link>
 http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Jul27_10-Dry-Weather-Reduces-Estimates-of-Brazils-Sugarcane-Production
</link>
<guid>
http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Jul27_10-Dry-Weather-Reduces-Estimates-of-Brazils-Sugarcane-Production
</guid>
</item>

<item>
<title>
July 26, 2010: Argentina and China Fail to Resolve Soybean Oil Dispute
</title>
<description>
One week after President Kirchner returned from an official visit to China, the Argentine government announced another round of higher import duties that will be levied on Chinese and Brazilian goods, specifically food processors.  This is the second time in 2010 that the Argentine government has accused the Chinese of dumping goods into the Argentine market.  The first antidumping accusation occurred in January of 2010 and it involved shoes and various industrial items.  In response, the Chinese government suspended the purchase of Argentine soybean oil in April of 2010.
</description>
<link>
http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Jul26_10-Argentina-and-China-Fail-To-Resolve-Soybean-Oil-Dispute
</link>
<guid>
http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Jul26_10-Argentina-and-China-Fail-To-Resolve-Soybean-Oil-Dispute
</guid>
</item>


<item>
<title>
July 26, 2010: Rate of Deforestation in Brazilian Amazon Region Fell 47% in 2010
</title>
<description>
The Brazilian National Institute of Space Studies (Inpe) recently announced that between August 2009 and May 2010, 1,564 square kilometers of Amazon forest was cleared compared to 2,958 square kilometers cleared during the same period a year earlier.  This represents a decline of 47% in the rate of deforestation in the Amazon Region of Brazil.
</description>
<link>
 http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Jul26_10-Rate-of-Deforestation-in-Brazil-Amazon-Region-Fell-47-in-2010
</link>
<guid>
http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Jul26_10-Rate-of-Deforestation-in-Brazil-Amazon-Region-Fell-47-in-2010
</guid>
</item>


<item>
<title>
July 23, 2010: Brazilian Farmers Continue to be Slow in Purchasing Inputs
</title>
<description>
Even though soybean prices have strengthened over the last month, it has not been enough to excite soybean farmers in Brazil who continue to be slow in purchasing their inputs for the 2010/11 crop.  One of the reasons for the lack of enthusiasm is the currency exchange rate.  Even though the March soybean price on the Chicago Broad of Trade increased 6.7% over the past 12 months, the Brazilian currency gained 6.8% over the same period.  A stronger Brazilian currency makes some of the inputs cheaper, but it also means that Brazilian farmers put less money in their pockets every time they sell a sack of soybeans.  Anytime the Brazilian currency is trading at 1.8 to the dollar or less, farmers view this as very negative.
</description>
<link>
http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Jul23_10-Brazilian-Farmers-Continue-to-be-Slow-in-Purchasing-Inputs
</link>
<guid>
http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Jul23_10-Brazilian-Farmers-Continue-to-be-Slow-in-Purchasing-Inputs
</guid>
</item>


<item>
<title>
July 23, 2010: Higher Brazilian Ethanol Prices in 2010 Leads to Reduced Sales
</title>
<description>
Higher ethanol prices in Brazil during the first half of 2010 resulted in a 17% drop in ethanol consumption compared to the same period in 2009.  During the same period, gasoline consumption in Brazil increased 22%.   According to the National Petroleum Agency (ANP) ethanol consumption in Brazil during the January to May period totaled 5.3 billion liters compared to 6.4 billion liters during the same period in 2009.
</description>
<link>
 http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Jul23_10-High-Brazilian-Ethanol-Prices-in-2010-Leads-to-Reduced-Sales
</link>
<guid>
http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Jul23_10-High-Brazilian-Ethanol-Prices-in-2010-Leads-to-Reduced-Sales
</guid>
</item>


<item>
<title>
July 22, 2010: Corn Yields and Prices Disappoint Mato Grosso Farmers
</title>
<description>
Farmers in Mato Grosso are finishing up harvesting the <i>safrinha</i> corn crop and they continue to work on harvesting the state's cotton crop.  Both crops were adversely affected by the early onset of the dry season and disappointing yields have been reported.  
</description>
<link>
http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Jul22_10-Corn-Yields-and-Prices-Disappoint-Mato-Grosso-Farmers
</link>
<guid>
http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Jul22_10-Corn-Yields-and-Prices-Disappoint-Mato-Grosso-Farmers
</guid>
</item>

<item>
<title>
July 21, 2010: Brazilian Meteorologists Worried About Developing La Nina
</title>
<description>
As a La Nina develops in the eastern Pacific, Brazilian meteorologists are predicting an increased chance of dryer than normal conditions during the Brazilian spring and summer growing season.  The last La Nina, which occurred during the 2007/08 growing season, had a minimal affect on the Brazilian crops, but it developed late in the growing season.  Its principal affect occurred during the start of the 2008/09 growing season when a prolonged drought afflicted southern Brazil.  This La Nina is developing early, even before the growing season has started, and it has the potential to be much more intense than the last one.
</description>
<link>
http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Jul21_10-Brazilian-Meteorologists-Worried-About-Developing-La-Nina
</link>
<guid>
http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Jul21_10-Brazilian-Meteorologists-Worried-About-Developing-La-Nina
</guid>
</item>

<item>
<title>
July 21, 2010: Brazil Moving Ahead on Cellulosic Ethanol Research
</title>
<description>
Currently, cellulosic ethanol is too expensive to compete with sugarcane based or corn based ethanol, but that may change soon in Brazil.  The Brazilian National Laboratory for Bioethanol Science and Technology (CTBE) located in Campinas, Sao Paulo, in the process of building a R$ 24 million pilot plant designed to develop new technologies for economic cellulosic ethanol production. The plant should be ready for start up operations sometime next year.
</description>
<link>
http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Jul21_10-Brazil-Moving-Ahead-on-Cellulosic-Ethanol-Research
</link>
<guid>
http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Jul21_10-Brazil-Moving-Ahead-on-Cellulosic-Ethanol-Research
</guid>
</item>


<item>
<title>
July 20, 2010: Arctic Blast Hits Southern South America
</title>
<description>
During the last week, one of the coldest air masses in decades has resulted in record low temperatures in all of southern South America from Tierra del Fuego to the Amazon.  The city of Buenos Aires had its biggest snowfall in nearly a century.  In fact, since late last week, twelve of Argentina's provinces recorded snowfall.  All of southern Brazil experienced repeated hard freezes with temperatures in the mid-20.  Snow was recorded in some of the higher elevations of southern Brazil.  Over a thousand cattle were killed by the freezing temperatures in Mato Grosso do Sul.  Even in Mato Grosso, near freezing temperatures were experienced for three consecutive nights.  The coldest temperatures were seen over the weekend and now the cold seems to be moderating, but it was one for the record books.
</description>
<link>
http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Jul20_10-Artic-Blast-Hits-Southern-Brazil
</link>
<guid>
http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Jul20_10-Artic-Blast-Hits-Southern-Brazil
</guid>
</item>

<item>
<title>
July 20, 2010: Cold Has No Impact on Grain Production, But Could Impact Fruit 
</title>
<description>
Then record cold temperatures are not expected to adversely affect the winter crops in southern South America.  Wheat is the major crop that is currently growing in southern South America.  Since the wheat is in vegetative development, agronomists in Parana and Rio Grande do Sul feel the cold temperatures will have no adverse affect and could actually benefit the crop.  Farmers in Argentina also feel the cold temperatures did not harm the wheat crop at all.
</description>
<link>
http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Jul20_10-Cold-Has-No-Impact-on-Grain-Production-Could-Impact-Fruit
</link>
<guid>
http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Jul20_10-Cold-Has-No-Impact-on-Grain-Production-Could-Impact-Fruit
</guid>
</item>

<item>
<title>
July 19, 2010: "Soja Louca 2" or "Crazy Soybean 2" Puzzles Brazilian Scientists
</title>
<description>
Brazilian farmers and scientists are puzzled about a previously unknown anomaly that has appeared in Brazilian soybean fields.  Scientists do not know if it is a disease or some type of chemical interaction.  The anomaly is being called "soja louca II" or "crazy soybean 2".  The anomaly was seen in all of the major producing states in Brazil last year, but Mato Grosso registered the most occurrences.  In its most severe form, farmers reported loosing 100 or 200 hectares of soybeans.
</description>
<link>
http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Jul19_10-Soja-Lucas-2-or-Crazy-Soybean-2-Puzzles-Brazilian-Scientist
</link>
<guid>
http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Jul19_10-Soja-Lucas-2-or-Crazy-Soybean-2-Puzzles-Brazilian-Scientist
</guid>
</item>

<item>
<title>
July 19, 2010: Increased Palm Oil Production Being Promoted in Brazil
</title>
<description>
The ever expanding use of palm oil in Brazil has convinced many in the agricultural sector that Brazil is missing out on tremendous opportunity to increase palm oil production within the country.  Brazil is currently importing approximately 50% of the palm oil used domestically for food products, soaps, cosmetics, industrial uses, and even biofuel production.  Ironically, Brazil is the one large tropical country that has the land area and the climate that would be ideal for palm oil production.
</description>
<link>
http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Jul19_10-Increased-Palm-Oil-Production-Being-Promoted-in-Brazil
</link>
<guid>
http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Jul19_10-Increased-Palm-Oil-Production-Being-Promoted-in-Brazil
</guid>
</item>


<item>
<title>
July 16, 2010: Brazil Maintains Its Leadership of the "Breakfast Commodities"
</title>
<description>
Brazil is one of the leading agricultural exporters in the world and when it comes to the so called "breakfast commodities" coffee, frozen orange juice, and sugar, it is the number one producer in the world.  In addition, Brazil is one of the leading producers and exporters of beef, poultry, pork, soybeans, corn, tobacco, and ethanol.
</description>
<link>
http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Jul16_10-Brazil-Maintains-its-Leadership-of-the-Breakfast-Commodities
</link>
<guid>
http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Jul16_10-Brazil-Maintains-its-Leadership-of-the-Breakfast-Commodities
</guid>
</item>

<item>
<title>
July 16, 2010: Brazilian Sugarcane Producers Increase Investments in 2010/11  
</title>
<description>
For the last two years, sugarcane producers in southern Brazil have cut back on the amount of money they were willing to invest in their sugarcane crop due to the low prices processors were willing to pay for the raw sugarcane.  With sugarcane prices improving, it looks like 2010 will be a recovery year for sugarcane producers and as a result; they are now more willing to make the necessary investments in the crop.  According to the Organization of Sugarcane Growers in the Central South, sugarcane producers in southern Brazil are poised to invest R$ 5 billion in production upgrades.
</description>
<link>
http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Jul16_10-Brazil-Sugarcane-Produces-Increase-Investment-in-201011
</link>
<guid>
http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Jul16_10-Brazil-Sugarcane-Produces-Increase-Investment-in-201011
</guid>
</item>

<item>
<title>
July 15, 2010: Brazilian Justice Dept. Trying to Determine How Much Farmland Owned by Foreigners
</title>
<description>
There has been a lot of concern recently in Brazil about farmland being purchased by foreign individuals and foreign governments.  The Brazilian Congress is considering legislation which would limit the amount of land a foreigner can purchase, but before legislation can be passed, the Brazilian Justice Department is trying to determine just how much land has been purchased by foreigners.
</description>
<link>
http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Jul15_10-Brazilian-Justice-Dept-Trying-to-Determine-How-Much-Farmland-Owned-by-Foreigners
</link>
<guid>
http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Jul15_10-Brazilian-Justice-Dept-Trying-to-Determine-How-Much-Farmland-Owned-by-Foreigners
</guid>
</item>

<item>
<title>
July 15, 2010: Early Maturing Cotton Shows Promise in Mato Grosso
</title>
<description>
Initial yield results of cotton being harvested in Mato Grosso indicate that short-stature early maturing cotton could be a viable alternative to traditional cotton production in the state.  Short stature cotton is planted in narrow rows, 45 cm (18 inches), compared to traditional cotton which is planted in 76 to 90 cm row spacing (30 to 36 inch rows).  It is shorter in height than traditional cotton and it matures in 170 days compared to 210 days for traditional cotton.
</description>
<link>
http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Jul15_10-Early-Maturing-Cotton-Shows-Promise-in-Mato-Grosso
</link>
<guid>
http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Jul15_10-Early-Maturing-Cotton-Shows-Promise-in-Mato-Grosso
</guid>
</item>

<item>
<title>
July 14, 2010: Soybeans Account for Only 0.25% of Recent Amazon Deforestation
</title>
<description>
Due to efforts of environmentalists, multinational grain companies, soybean processors, soybean exporters, the federal government, and various farm organizations, soybean cultivation in Brazil was responsible for 0.25% of the Amazon Rainforest that has been cleared over the last three years.  Data released by participants of the Soybean Moratorium Program indicate that 2,480,000 hectares of Amazon Rainforest were cleared since 2006, but soybeans were planted on only 6,295 of those hectares.  This calculation was based on satellite data provided by the Brazilian Space Institute.  
</description>
<link>
http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Jul14_10-Soybean-Account-for-Only-025-of-Recent-Amazon-Deforestation
</link>
<guid>
http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Jul14_10-Soybean-Account-for-Only-025-of-Recent-Amazon-Deforestation
</guid>
</item>

<item>
<title>
July 14, 2010: Safrinha Corn Harvest in Parana Depresses Domestic Corn Prices
</title>
<description>
The <i>safrinha</i> corn harvest in Parana is 20% complete and as the harvest pace accelerates; the excess corn in the marketplace has depressed prices and convinced most farmers to hold onto their corn in hopes of better prices in the future.  Only 5% of the anticipated <i>safrinha</i> corn production in the state has been forward sold as farmers opt to store the crop.  Additionally, Parana farmers are still holding onto 40% of their full season corn production as well.  There is already 4.5 million tons of corn in storage in the state and that may double before the end of the <i>safrinha</i> harvest.  The lack of storage space in the state is going to get worse before it gets better.
</description>
<link>
http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Jul14_10-Safrinha-Corn-Harvest-in-Parana-Depresses-Domestic-Corn-Prices
</link>
<guid>
http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Jul14_10-Safrinha-Corn-Harvest-in-Parana-Depresses-Domestic-Corn-Prices
</guid>
</item>

<item>
<title>
July 13, 2010: Trip Report - Ohio and Indiana
</title>
<description>
Last Thursday I took a crop tour through central and northern Indiana as well as northwestern and western Ohio with the following observations:
</description>
<link>
http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Jul13_10-Trip-Report-Ohio-and-Indiana
</link>
<guid>
http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Jul13_10-Trip-Report-Ohio-and-Indiana
</guid>
</item>

<item>
<title>
July 13, 2010: Raw Commodities Account for Nearly Half of Brazil's Exportsop
</title>
<description>
Due to primarily Chinese demand, Brazil's exports of raw commodities, including both agricultural and mineral, now account for 43% of all Brazilian exports.  A decade ago, raw commodities accounted for only 22.8% of Brazilian exports.  In contrast, over the same period, the percentage of Brazilian exports classified as manufactured or semi-manufactured fell from 75% of the total in 2000 to 54% of the total in 2009.
</description>
<link>
http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/July13_10-Raw-Commodities-Account-for-Nearly-Half-Brazil%27s-Exports
</link>
<guid>
http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/July13_10-Raw-Commodities-Account-for-Nearly-Half-Brazil%27s-Exports
</guid>
</item>

<item>
<title>
July 12, 2010: Brazilian Scientists Focusing on Reducing Fertilizer Imports		
</title>
<description>
Brazil imports 90% of its potassium fertilizer, which has many farmers and government officials concerned due to the recent volatility of fertilizer prices.  After fertilizer prices doubled during the 2007/08 growing season, the Brazilian government started a concerted effort to reduce its dependence on imported fertilizer by finding and developing more domestic supplies of fertilizers.  Their most recent effort has been the formation of a research network called Rede FertBrasil.

</description>
<link>
http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Jul12_10-Brazilian-Scientist-Focusing-on-Reucing-Fertilizer-Imports
</link>
<guid>
http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Jul12_10-Brazilian-Scientist-Focusing-on-Reucing-Fertilizer-Imports
</guid>
</item>

<item>
<title>
July 12, 2010: Safrinha Corn Estimates in Mato Grosso Continue to Decline	
</title>
<description>
The two main governmental agencies that estimate crop production in the state of Mato Grosso have once again lowered their estimates for the 2010 <i>safrinha</i> corn crop in Mato Grosso.  In its weekly report, the Mato Grosso Institute of Agricultural Economics (Imea) lowered its estimate of the <i>safrinha</i> corn production in Mato Grosso.  They estimate the farmers in Mato Grosso planted 2 million hectares of <i>safrinha</i> corn (a record), but due to dry weather, the total corn production will be down at least 3.5% compared to the 8.5 million tons produced last year.  Their current estimate of the <i>safrinha</i> corn crop is 8.2 million tons with an average yield of 4,099 kg/ha or 63 bu/ac.
</description>
<link>
http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Jul12_10-Safrinha-Corn-Estimates-in-Mato-Grosso-Continue-to-Decline
</link>
<guid>
http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Jul12_10-Safrinha-Corn-Estimates-in-Mato-Grosso-Continue-to-Decline
</guid>
</item>



<item>
<title>
July 9, 2010: Brazilian Farmers Are Slow to Purchase Inputs for 2010/11 Crop
</title>
<description>
Even though the costs of inputs are lower this year compared to last year, farmers in central Brazil have been slow to purchase their inputs for the 2010/11 crop due mainly to a shortage of credit and cash.  For many years the farmers in Mato Grosso have been relying on the multinational grain companies for much of the credit they needed to plant their crops.  With the economic downturn of the last few years, these companies have significantly cut back on the level of credit they are willing to extend to the farmers.  
</description>
<link>
http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Jul9_10-Brazilian-Farmers-are-Slow-to-Purchase-Inputs-for-201011-Crop
</link>
<guid>
http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Jul9_10-Brazilian-Farmers-are-Slow-to-Purchase-Inputs-for-201011-Crop
</guid>
</item>

<item>
<title>
July 9, 2010: Dry Weather Accelerates Sugarcane Harvest in Southeastern Brazil
</title>
<description>
Dry weather in southeastern Brazil is providing several benefits for sugarcane producers in the region.  In addition to encouraging a rapid harvest and processing pace, the sugarcane being harvested is of higher quality as well.  June rainfall in southeastern Brazil has been 54% of the historical average and this is after a dryer than normal April and May.
</description>
<link>
http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Jul9_10-Dry-Weather-Accelerates-Sugarcane-Harvest-in-Southeastern-Brazil
</link>
<guid>
http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Jul9_10-Dry-Weather-Accelerates-Sugarcane-Harvest-in-Southeastern-Brazil
</guid>
</item>

<item>
<title>
July 8, 2010: Heavy Rains in Central Corn Belt Take Toll on Corn and Soy Crops
</title>
<description>
Over the weekend I traveled through Illinois, Iowa, southwestern Minnesota, eastern South Dakota, and eastern Nebraska.  I am only going to comment on the crops I saw along my path which included:  Chicago, Iowa City (IA), Waterloo (IA), Fort Dodge (IA), Spencer (IA), Redwood Falls (MN), Brookings (SD), Yankton (SD), Norfolk (NE), Columbus (NE), Omaha (NE), Red Oak (IA), Ottumwa (IA), Burlington (IA), Macomb (IL), Bloomington (IA), Chicago.
</description>
<link>
http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Jul8_10-Heavy-Rains-in-Central-Corn-Belt-Take-Toll-on-Corn-and-Soy-Crops
</link>
<guid>
http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Jul8_10-Heavy-Rains-in-Central-Corn-Belt-Take-Toll-on-Corn-and-Soy-Crops
</guid>
</item>

<item>
<title>
July 6, 2010: Cotton Acreage to Increase in Brazil at Expense of Soybean Acreage
</title>
<description>
Farmers in Brazil are expected to increase their cotton acreage 15% to 20% more during the 2010/11 growing season as compared to 2009/10.  According the Mato Grosso Cotton Producers Association, the cotton acreage in Mato Grosso, which is Brazil's largest cotton producing state, could increase up to 15% from 422,000 hectares to 483,000 hectares.  Cotton acreage in Bahia is expected to increase 50,000 hectares next year and in Goias it is expected to increase 25,000 hectares.  In all of Brazil, 836,000 hectares of cotton were planted last growing season.
</description>
<link>
http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/July6_10-Cotton-Acreage-to-Increase-in-Brazil-at-Expense-of-Soybean-Acreage
</link>
<guid>
http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/July6_10-Cotton-Acreage-to-Increase-in-Brazil-at-Expense-of-Soybean-Acreage
</guid>
</item>

<item>
<title>
June 28, 2010: Conventional Soybeans Finding Niche in Brazil
</title>
<description>
According to the Mato Grosso Institute of Agricultural Economics (Imea) during the 2009/10 growing season 54% of the soybeans produced in Mato Grosso were genetically modified.  The percentage is expected to increase to 60% for the 2010/11 growing season and may eventually hit 70%.
</description>
<link>
http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Jun28_10-Convetional-Soybeans-Finding-Niche-in-Brazil
</link>
<guid>
http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Jun28_10-Convetional-Soybeans-Finding-Niche-in-Brazil
</guid>
</item>

<item>
<title>
June 28, 2010: Biodiesel Could Become Driving Factor for Soybean Demand in Brazil
</title>
<description>
The increased use of biodiesel in Brazil could become the driving factor for internal soybean demand in Brazil especially since the total soybean production in 2010/11 is not expected to equal the superb results obtained in 2009/11.  During the last growing season, Brazil produced 10 million tons of soybeans more than the previous year, but the total soybean production is expected to decline in 2010/11.
</description>
<link>
http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Jun28_10-Biodisel-Could-Become-Driving-Factor-for-Soybean-Demand-in-Brazil
</link>
<guid>
http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Jun28_10-Biodisel-Could-Become-Driving-Factor-for-Soybean-Demand-in-Brazil
</guid>
</item>

<item>
<title>
June 25, 2010: Copersucar to Process 30% of Brazil's Sugarcane Within Five Years
</title>
<description>
Copersucar continues its aggressive growth in the Brazilian sugarcane market.  According to Paulo Roberto de Souza, president of the company, Copersucar plans to expand its sugarcane processing capacity by 75% over the next five years.  During the 2010/11 growing season, they will process 85 million tons of sugarcane and that is expected to increase to 200 million tons by 2015.  If realized, that would represent 30% of the sugarcane processed in Brazil.
</description>
<link>
http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Jun25_10-Copersucar-to-Process-30-of-Brazils-Sugarcane-in-Five-Years
</link>
<guid>
http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Jun25_10-Copersucar-to-Process-30-of-Brazils-Sugarcane-in-Five-Years
</guid>
</item>

<item>
<title>
June 25, 2010: Los Grobo from Argentina Increasing its Presence in Brazil
</title>
<description>
The Argentine company known as Los Grobo, which is already one of the principal agricultural companies in Mercosul, is focusing its ambitious expansion plans in Brazil.  Los Grobo originated in Argentina, but has been expanding rapidly in recent years into Brazil, Paraguay, and Uruguay.  According to its president, Gustavo Grobocopatel, the company plans to originate 800,000 tons of soybeans across all of its operations in 2010/11 with the ultimate goal of originating 3 million tons of soybeans.
</description>
<link>
http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Jun25_10-Los-Grobo-from-Argetina-Increasing-its-Presence-in-Brazil
</link>
<guid>
http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Jun25_10-Los-Grobo-from-Argetina-Increasing-its-Presence-in-Brazil
</guid>
</item>

<item>
<title>
June 24, 2010: Soybean Acreage in Mato Grosso Could be Down 2% in 2010/11
</title>
<description>
The first survey of farmers in Mato Grosso conducted by the Mato Grosso Institute of Agriculture Economics (Imea) indicates that they intend to reduce their soybean acreage for the 2010/11 growing season which will start later in September.  The survey points to a reduction of 2% in soybean acreage from 6.21 million hectares planted during last growing season to 6.09 million hectares expected to be planted in 2010/11.  
</description>
<link>
http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Jun24_10-Soybean-Acreage-in-Mato-Grosso-Could-be-Down-2-in-201011
</link>
<guid>
http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Jun24_10-Soybean-Acreage-in-Mato-Grosso-Could-be-Down-2-in-201011
</guid>
</item>

<item>
<title>
June 24, 2010: Lack of Storage Continues to be a Problem in Mato Grosso
</title>
<description>
Even with the federal government purchasing corn on a weekly basis in Mato Grosso, there is still not enough storage space in the state to accommodate all the corn and soybeans at the same time.  According to the Mato Grosso Institute of Agricultural Economics, farmers in Mato Grosso have harvested approximately 12% of their 2.0 million hectares of <i>safrinha</i> corn production and they are having a hard time finding a place to store the corn.  A lot of the silos in the state are still being occupied by soybeans since many farmers are waiting for improved prices before they sell their production and the situation is only expected to get worse as the corn harvest progresses.
</description>
<link>
http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Jun24_10-Lack-of-Storage-Continues-to-be-a-Problem-in-Mato-Grosso
</link>
<guid>
http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Jun24_10-Lack-of-Storage-Continues-to-be-a-Problem-in-Mato-Grosso
</guid>
</item>

<item>
<title>
June 23, 2010: Central Corn Belt Receiving Too Much of a Good Thing
</title>
<description>
Heavy rains continue to sweep across the central Corn Belt leaving saturated soils and standing water in their wake.  The nation's soil moisture held steady last week, but the situation was anything but static.  The soils in the central Corn Belt got wetter while the soils in the Delta got dryer.  The soils in Illinois for example are rated as 60% saturated, Iowa has 55% saturated conditions, Ohio has 53%, and Indiana has 52% saturated.  In contrast, the soils in Arkansas are rated as 60% short to very short, Louisiana has 51% short, and Mississippi is 39% short.  Some farmers in southern Iowa and northern Missouri have not been able to get into their fields at all during the month of June.
</description>
<link>
http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Jun23_10-Central-Corn-Belt-Receiving-Too-Much-of-a-Good-Thing
</link>
<guid>
http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Jun23_10-Central-Corn-Belt-Receiving-Too-Much-of-a-Good-Thing
</guid>
</item>

<item>
<title>
June 23, 2010: Brazil Experimenting With a 60-day Cotton Free Period
</title>
<description>
By the end of June virtually all the principal soybean producing states in Brazil will enter into the period when no live soybeans will be allowed either on farms or around commercial grain facilities.  This soybean-free program started about five years ago and is credited with delaying the onset of soybean rust into commercial soybean fields.  The spores of soybean rust can not live more than 60 days without a host plant so the idea is to eliminate the host plants as much as possible in order to break the life cycle of the disease.  The most common host plant is soybeans so there is a very concerted effort to make sure there are no soybeans growing during this period.  Legitimate soybean research plots and seed increases are exempt, but they must be licensed and closely monitored by state agencies to insure that the soybean rust is under control.
</description>
<link>
http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Jun23_10-Brazil-Expeirmenting-With-a-60-Day-Cotton-Free-Period
</link>
<guid>
http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Jun23_10-Brazil-Expeirmenting-With-a-60-Day-Cotton-Free-Period
</guid>
</item>

<item>
<title>
June 21, 2010: The Dry Season Has Begun in Central Brazil
</title>
<description>
This report is being sent from Rondonopolis, in southeastern Mato Grosso.  Here in central Brazil it is now the dry season.  The last significant rain in Rondonopolis was about a month ago and the total rainfall since early April has been about 1.5 inches.  Generally during the months of June, July, and August the only rains that fall in central Brazil are the light and drizzly type of rains that accompany strong cold fronts that manage to make it this close to the equator.  The next significant rain is not expected until later in August or early in September.  The first rain at the end of the dry season is called the "mango rain" because it helps the development of the mangoes which are already developing by then.  The leaves are starting to fall and by the end of the dry season, some of the native cerrado trees will be devoid of leaves. 
</description>
<link>
http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Jun21_10-The-Dry-Season-Has-Begun-in-Central-Brazil
</link>
<guid>
http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Jun21_10-The-Dry-Season-Has-Begun-in-Central-Brazil
</guid>
</item>

<item>
<title>
June 21, 2010: Soybean and Corn Prices Not Very Encouraging for Brazilian Farmers
</title>
<description>
Soybean farmers in Mato Grosso just finished the growing season with the lowest profits in four years.  Profits this year are averaging R$ 140 per hectare (US$ 56 per acre) compared to R$ 150 per hectare (US$ 60 per acre) for the 2008-09 growing season.  The main reasons for the lower profitability are lower commodity prices and a stronger local currency.
</description>
<link>
http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Jun21_10-Soybean-and-Corn-Prices-Not-Very-Encouraging-For-Brazilian-Farmers
</link>
<guid>
http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Jun21_10-Soybean-and-Corn-Prices-Not-Very-Encouraging-For-Brazilian-Farmers
</guid>
</item>

<item>
<title>
June 17, 2010: Brazilian Government Running Out of Space to Store Wheat
</title>
<description>
The Brazilian government not only tries to support the price of corn and soybeans, it does the same for wheat as well.  In the state of Parana for example, the minimum guaranteed price for wheat is between R$ 31.80 to R$ 33.30 per sack of 60 kilograms for the best grades of wheat (US$ 9.00 to 9.25 a bushel), but the current cash price for wheat in Parana is approximately R$ 22.00 per sack or US$ 6.10 a bushel.  As you might suspect, everybody wants to sell their wheat to the government at the minimum price.
</description>
<link>
http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Jun17_10-Brazilian-Government-Running-Out-of-Space-to-Store-Wheat
</link>
<guid>
http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Jun17_10-Brazilian-Government-Running-Out-of-Space-to-Store-Wheat
</guid>
</item>

<item>
<title>
June 17, 2010: Lack of Infrastructure Costs Brazilian Farmers R$ 1 Billion
</title>
<description>
Brazil has a huge amount of land that can be converted into new agricultural production, but ironically the most expensive place to grow soybeans in Brazil is on these newly cleared lands. The primary reason why it is so expensive to grow soybeans on these new lands is the ultra high cost of transportation needed to move the product to processors or export facilities.
</description>
<link>
http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Jun17_10-Lack-of-Infrastructure-Costs-Brazilian-Farmers-1-Billion
</link>
<guid>
http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Jun17_10-Lack-of-Infrastructure-Costs-Brazilian-Farmers-1-Billion
</guid>
</item>

<item>
<title>
June 16, 2010: Truckers Forced to Wait Two Days to Unload Soybeans in Parana
</title>
<description>
The combination of a record large crop and inadequate infrastructure continues to cause problems in Brazil.  Take for example the Imcopa Grain Company in the city of Cambe located in northern Parana.  Last week, the line of trucks waiting at their facility to unload soybeans from Mato Grosso stretched more than ten kilometers along the highway  and the truckers were forced to wait for two days or longer before they could unload their cargo.
</description>
<link>
http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Jun16_10-Truckers-Forced-to-Wait-Two-Days-to-Unload-Soybeans-in-Parana
</link>
<guid>
http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Jun16_10-Truckers-Forced-to-Wait-Two-Days-to-Unload-Soybeans-in-Parana
</guid>
</item>

<item>
<title>
June 16, 2010: Lumber Extracted from Amazon Region Halved in Ten Years
</title>
<description>
The amount of lumber extracted from the Brazilian Lowland Amazon Region fell by half between 1998 and 2009 from 28.3 million cubic meters per year to 14.2 million cubic meters per year.  The decline is attributed to several factors including: the substitution of eucalyptus for native hardwoods, increased monitoring and enforcement of environmental laws, and lower demand due to the worldwide economic slowdown.
</description>
<link>
http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Jun16_10-Lumber-Extracted-from-Amazon-Region-Halved-in-Ten-Years
</link>
<guid>
http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Jun16_10-Lumber-Extracted-from-Amazon-Region-Halved-in-Ten-Years
</guid>
</item>

<item>
<title>
June 15, 2010: Drowned Out Corn Results in Reduced Harvested Acreage
</title>
<description>
After weeks of saturated conditions it appears that some of the drowned out corn will not be replanted to corn or any other crop, but instead, it will be claimed as prevent plant under the provisions of the crop insurance program.  This could be a particular problem in northern Nebraska, southern Iowa, northern Missouri, central Illinois, central Indiana, northwestern Ohio, and southern Michigan.  In virtually all of these areas it will be too late to plant corn once the soils dry out.  If a farmer purchased crop insurance with eighty five percent coverage, he would be much better off economically to collect the insurance payment instead of planting another crop at such a late date. 
</description>
<link>
http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Jun15_10-Drowned-Corn-Results-in-Reduced-Harvested-Acreage
</link>
<guid>
http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Jun15_10-Drowned-Corn-Results-in-Reduced-Harvested-Acreage
</guid>
</item>

<item>
<title>
June 15, 2010: Corn-on-corn Struggling Under Saturated Conditions
</title>
<description>
In the saturated regions of the central Corn Belt, it appears that corn-on-corn is not faring as well as corn-on-soybeans.  This was evident once again last week when I traveled through western Indiana.  You see excellent corn fields right aside of corn fields that look poor.  The excellent fields are thigh high, deep green, very uniform in height, and obviously in excellent condition.  The corn-on-corn fields are shorter, uneven in height, pale green in color, and obviously struggling.
</description>
<link>
http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Jun15_10-Corn-on-corn-Struggling-Under-Saturated-Conditions
</link>
<guid>
http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Jun15_10-Corn-on-corn-Struggling-Under-Saturated-Conditions
</guid>
</item>

<item>
<title>
June 14, 2010: Sugarcane Replacing Oranges in the State of Sao Paulo
</title>
<description>
Farmers in the state of Sao Paulo are reducing their orange orchards in favor of growing more sugarcane.  After suffering through years of low prices, increased disease pressure, increased costs, and occasional frosts, orange growers in Sao Paulo have decided to cut back on orange production and to increase sugarcane production.  According to a recent survey conducted in the state, 38% of the orange growers in Sao Paulo said they are reducing their orange acreage and 58% of those respondents said they are increasing their sugarcane acreage.
</description>
<link>
http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Jun14_10-Sugarcane-Replacing-Oranges-in-the-State-of-Sao-Paulo
</link>
<guid>
http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Jun14_10-Sugarcane-Replacing-Oranges-in-the-State-of-Sao-Paulo
</guid>
</item>


<item>
<title>
June 14, 2010: Mechanical Sugarcane Harvesting Reduces Greenhouse Gas Emissions
</title>
<description>
Mechanical sugarcane harvesting in Brazil is rapidly replacing the prior practice of harvesting the sugarcane by hand.  Not only is mechanical harvesting more efficient, it also reduces greenhouse gas emissions, it improves the fertility of the soil, it improves the quality of the ground water, and it helps to sequester larger amounts of carbon compared to harvesting the sugarcane by hand.
</description>
<link>
http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Jun14_10-Mechanical-Sugarcane-Harvesting-Reduces-Greenhouse-Gas-Emissions
</link>
<guid>
http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Jun14_10-Mechanical-Sugarcane-Harvesting-Reduces-Greenhouse-Gas-Emissions
</guid>
</item>

<item>
<title>
June 10, 2010: Ranchers in Brazil Want to Eliminate Vaccinations for Foot and Mouth Disease
</title>
<description>
In Brazil, if foot and mouth disease has not been found in the cattle herd of a particular state for more than 14 years, the state has the right to petition the Minister of Agriculture to eliminate the requirement that all the cattle in the state be vaccinated twice a year against the disease.  The cattle herds in three Brazilian states, Parana, Santa Catarina, and Mato Grosso meet those requirements and as a result, officials in these three states are contemplating just such a move...
</description>
<link>
http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Jun10_10-Rachers-in-Brazil-Want-to-Eliminate-Vaccinations-for-Foot-And-Mouth-Disese
</link>
<guid>
http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Jun10_10-Rachers-in-Brazil-Want-to-Eliminate-Vaccinations-for-Foot-And-Mouth-Disese
</guid>
</item>

<item>
<title>
June 9, 2010: Central Corn Belt Crops Receiving Too Much or Too Little Rain
</title>
<description>
The crops in the central Corn Belt are generally in good condition, but there are areas where the crops are less than ideal.  Excessive rains in southern Iowa, northern Missouri, central Illinois, central Indiana, and northwestern Ohio has led to a significant amount of standing water and drowned out crops.  In contrast, northern Iowa, eastern South Dakota and most of southern Minnesota has received less than the normal amount of rainfall over the last thirty days, but they have received rain over the last few days...
</description>
<link>
http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Jun9_10-Central-Corn-Belt-Crops-Receiving-Too-Much-or-Too-LIttle-Rain
</link>
<guid>
http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Jun9_10-Central-Corn-Belt-Crops-Receiving-Too-Much-or-Too-LIttle-Rain
</guid>
</item>

<item>
<title>
June 9, 2010: Accuracy of June Planted Report Now in Doubt
</title>
<description>
This week, the USDA is finishing the nationwide survey for the June Planted Report, which will be released on June 30th.  Since the corn crop had been planted earlier than normal this year, it was assumed that the planted report would be quite accurate, but that assumption may now be in doubt.  The heavy rains across southern Iowa, northern Missouri, central Illinois, north-central Indiana, and northwestern Ohio has drowned out some of the crops which now must either be replanted, claimed under insurance, or switched to another crop...
</description>
<link>
http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Jun9_10-Accuracy-of-June-Planted-Report-Now-in-Doubt
</link>
<guid>
http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Jun9_10-Accuracy-of-June-Planted-Report-Now-in-Doubt
</guid>
</item>

<item>
<title>
June 8, 2010: Brazil Announces New Plan to Build On-Farm Storage
</title>
<description>
A chronic problem for Brazilian farmers is a lack of on-farm storage that limits their options for selling their crops.  Estimates are that less than 15% of Brazil's grain production is stored on the farm.  As a way to address this problem, the Brazilian Minister of Agriculture, Wagner Rossi, recently announced a program to extend credit to farmers for the specific purpose of constructing on-farm storage.  A total of R$ 2 billion will be available through this program...	
</description>
<link>
http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Jun8_10-Brazil-Announces-New-Plan-to-Build-on-Farm-Storage
</link>
<guid>
http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Jun8_10-Brazil-Announces-New-Plan-to-Build-on-Farm-Storage
</guid>
</item>

<item>
<title>
June 8, 2010: Wet Weather Delays Wheat Planting in Rio Grande do Sul
</title>
<description>
Heavy rains and saturated soils are delaying the planting of the 2010 wheat crop in Rio Grande do Sul.  In the northern part of the state, where nearly all the winter wheat is grown, only 10% of the anticipated wheat acreage has been planted, which is significantly behind the normal pace.  Normally, wheat in Rio Grande do Sul is planted in June and harvested in November.  Virtually all the wheat in the state is followed by a second crop of soybeans...
</description>
<link>
http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Jun8_10-Wet-Weather-Delays-Wheat-Planting-in-Rio-Grande-do-Sul
</link>
<guid>
http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Jun8_10-Wet-Weather-Delays-Wheat-Planting-in-Rio-Grande-do-Sul
</guid>
</item>

<item>
<title>
June 7, 2010: 7% of Brazil's Soybeans Used for Biodiesel Production
</title>
<description>
As of January 1, 2010, the biodiesel standard in Brazil was set at B5 or a mixture of 5% vegetable oil with 95% petroleum diesel.  Since 80% of the vegetable oil used to make biodiesel in Brazil is soybean oil, approximately 7% of Brazil's total soybean crop is now used to make the biodiesel blend.  To make the B5 blend, approximately 3.6 million tons of soybeans are needed or the equivalent of the soybeans produced on 1.2 million hectares of soybeans out of a total soybean acreage in 2009-10 of 23 million hectares.  In other terms, approximately one fourth of the soybean production in the state of Parana, which is the second leading producer in Brazil, is used for biodiesel production...
</description>
<link>
http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Jun7_10-7-of-Brazils-Soybeans-Used-for-Biodiesel-Production
</link>
<guid>
http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Jun7_10-7-of-Brazils-Soybeans-Used-for-Biodiesel-Production
</guid>
</item>

<item>
<title>
June 4, 2010: Cash Corn Prices Improving in Brazil
</title>
<description>
The first auction of corn was completed successfully last week in Brazil with the Brazilian government purchasing nearly a million tons of corn. These auctions are scheduled to be held on a weekly basis over the next eleven weeks.  The government needed to step in with these auctions because the cash price for corn in central Brazil was so low that no one was selling any of their corn.  At its lowest point, cash prices had dipped to below US$ 2.00 a bushel.  The minimum price the government is prepared to pay at these auctions is R$ 13.95 per sack or approximately US$ 3.95 a bushel...
</description>
<link>
http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Jun4_10-Cash-Corn-Prices-Improving-Brazil
</link>
<guid>
http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Jun4_10-Cash-Corn-Prices-Improving-Brazil
</guid>
</item>


<item>
<title>
June 4, 2010: Brazilian Cotton Crop Being Impacted by Dry Weather
</title>
<description>
Dry weather in central Brazil is not only impacting the <i>safrinha</i> corn crop, it is also impacting the cotton crop as well.  If the cotton was planted in December or early in January, it escaped the worst of the damage.  If the cotton was planted in mid-February or later, it has suffered significant yield losses due to the dry weather...

</description>
<link>
http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Jun4_10-Brazilian-Cotton-Crop-Being-Impacted-By-Dry-Weather
</link>
<guid>
http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Jun4_10-Brazilian-Cotton-Crop-Being-Impacted-By-Dry-Weather
</guid>
</item>

<item>
<title>
June 3, 2010: Over Half of U.S. Corn and Soybean Acreage in Top 5-6 States
</title>
<description>
At the start of each U.S. growing season, it's always good to recap where most of the corn and soybeans are grown so we have the right perspective when we discuss the condition of the crops in the various states.  Therefore, the chart below lists the top states as far as planted acreage is concerned...
</description>
<link>
http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Jun3_10-Over-Half-of-US-Corn-and-Soybean-Acreage-in-Top-5-6-States
</link>
<guid>
http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Jun3_10-Over-Half-of-US-Corn-and-Soybean-Acreage-in-Top-5-6-States
</guid>
</item>

<item>
<title>
June 3, 2010: Conventional Soybeans Maintaining Niche in Brazil
</title>
<description>
The use of Roundup Ready soybeans in Brazil continues to increase, but there is also a segment of Brazilian soybean farmers that feel that conventional soybeans may offer an advantage over GMO soybeans.  The advantages of conventional soybeans include lower priced seed, a premium for conventional soybeans paid by exporters, and less problems with resistant weeds.  There are disadvantages as well and they include the need to use higher priced herbicides to control weeds and less flexibility in herbicide applications... 
</description>
<link>
http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Jun3_10-Conventional-Soybeans-Maintaining-Niche-in-Brazil
</link>
<guid>
http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Jun3_10-Conventional-Soybeans-Maintaining-Niche-in-Brazil
</guid>
</item>


<item>
<title>
June 2, 2010: U.S. Crops Off to Good Start, No Major Concerns As Yet.
</title>
<description>
Corn planting in the U.S. advanced to 97% complete last week and the soybean planting advanced to 74% complete.  Last week's weather was also very beneficial for rapid emergence and stand establishment of the crops.  With the corn crop rated as 76% good to excellent and the soybean crop expected to be rated similar next week, both the corn and soybean crops continue to get off to a generally good start.  The long-range forecast for the first half of June indicates generally average to above average conditions for the next several weeks.  If that forecast verifies, both the corn and soybean crops should continue to develop normally... 
</description>
<link>
http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Jun2_10-US-Crops-Off-to-Good-Start-No-Major-Concern-Yet
</link>
<guid>
http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Jun2_10-US-Crops-Off-to-Good-Start-No-Major-Concern-Yet
</guid>
</item>

<item>
<title> 
June 1, 2010: Cost of Producing Soy in Mato Grosso Estimated at R$ 1,425/ha
</title>
<description>
For the 2010-11 growing season, the cost of producing soybeans in central Mato Grosso is estimated at R$ 1,425 per hectare (US$ 325 per acre), which is almost identical to the cost of production in 2009-10, but it's 27% cheaper than the R$ 1,955 per hectare (US$ 447 per acre) that it cost during the 2008-09 growing season. According to the Mato Grosso Institute of Agricultural Economics (Imea-MT), southeastern Mato Grosso will be the most expensive location to grow soybeans in 2010-11 at R$ 1,543 per hectare (US$ 352 per acre) followed by western Mato Grosso at R$ 1,504 per hectare (US$ 343 per acre)...
</description>
<link>
http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Jun1_10-Cost-of-Producing-Soy-in-Mato-Grosso-Estimated-at-1425
</link>
<guid>
http://soybeansandcorn.com/news/Jun1_10-Cost-of-Producing-Soy-in-Mato-Grosso-Estimated-at-1425
</guid>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
